If you have a belly sticking out, you
如果你的肚子凸出来，
the stomach, that's called visceral fat.
那就说明有问题了，因为胃里的脂肪叫做内脏脂肪。
This is very detrimental fat. And that's
这是非常有害的脂肪。 这就是
the epidemic that we have today. But the
我们今天面临的疫情。 但
only thing that will make you lose that
只有一种方法能让你
fat very quickly.
快速减掉脂肪。
&gt;&gt; Dr. Praep Jam Nadas is a worldleading
Praep Jam Nadas 博士是一位世界领先的
cardiologist
心脏病专家，他
&gt;&gt; who has treated more than a quarter of a
治疗过超过 25
million patients with chronic heart
万名慢性心脏病患者
disease.
。
&gt;&gt; Now he's using his voice to help
现在，他正利用自己的影响力，
operating table through simple lifestyle
通过简单的生活方式
techniques. This is crucial. Glucose
技巧，帮助数百万人避免最终坐上手术台。 这一点至关重要。 葡萄糖
actually is toxic inside the bloodstream
在血液中实际上是有毒的，
and the body cause insulin into the
身体会分泌胰岛素到
bloodstream to push glucose out. But
血液中，将葡萄糖排出体外。 但是
frequent consumption of carbs, sugar,
经常摄入碳水化合物、糖和
processed foods is causing insulin to
加工食品会导致胰岛素水平
stay up which can lead to insulin
居高不下，从而导致胰岛素
resistance and you're going to be more
抵抗，使你更
prone to heart disease which is the
容易患上心脏病，而心脏病是
world right now. But this is where
目前全世界的第一大死因。 但
fasting comes in because after 12 hours
禁食的作用就在于此，因为禁食 12 小时后，
you start pulling the fat out. And the
脂肪就开始被排出体外。
first place the fat comes out of is
脂肪最先从
going to be visceral fat. But with
内脏脂肪中释放出来。 但随着
modern living, we have lost this
现代生活方式的改变，我们已经失去了这种
physiology of fasting. So we'll go into
禁食的生理机能。 所以我们会深入探讨这个问题
that.
。
&gt;&gt; And there must be certain things which
而且，肯定有一些事情
people aren't aware aren't healthy as it
人们没有意识到，这些事情对
relates to my cardiovascular health.
我的心血管健康不利。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yes. So I see that people who overly do
。 我发现，过度进行
aerobic activity, they end up with more
有氧运动的人，
coronary artery disease than patients
比
who do short sprints and resistance
进行短跑和阻力
exercises. Then there's mold. And almost
训练的人更容易患上冠状动脉疾病。 然后还有霉菌。
70% of homes these days have some form
如今，近70%的家庭都存在某种形式的
of mold toxicity in them. But also one
霉菌毒性。 但是，仅仅一
night of bad sleep, you become insulin
晚睡眠不足，第二天就可能出现胰岛素
resistant the next day. And there's
抵抗。 还有
calcium supplements, excessive fruit.
钙补充剂，以及过量的水果。
White rice.
白米饭。
&gt;&gt; You'll be surprised how much arsenic
你会惊讶于
there's in rice these days.
如今大米中砷的含量之高。
&gt;&gt; I watch a lot of true crime. People kill
我经常看真实犯罪题材的节目。 人们
each other with arsenic.
用砒霜互相残杀。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yes. And it'll slowly kill you. And
。 它会慢慢杀死你。
lastly, this is going to surprise you.
最后，这件事可能会让你感到惊讶。
&gt;&gt; I see messages all the time in the
我经常在
comments section that some of you didn't
评论区看到有人留言说他们没有
realize you didn't subscribe. So, if you
意识到自己没有订阅。 所以，如果您
could do me a favor and double check if
能帮我个忙，再次确认一下
you're a subscriber to this channel,
您是否是本频道的订阅者，我
that would be tremendously appreciated.
将万分感激。
It's the simple. It's the free thing
就这么简单。 这是任何经常
that anybody that watches the show
观看该节目的人都
frequently can do to help us here to
可以做的免费事情，以帮助我们
keep everything going in this show in
保持该节目目前的良好发展
the trajectory it's on. So, please do
势头。 所以，请您
double check if you've subscribed and uh
再次确认是否已订阅，
thank you so much because in a strange
非常感谢，因为从某种意义上说，
way you are you're part of our history
您是我们历史的一部分，
and you're on this journey with us and I
您与我们一起踏上了这段旅程，我
appreciate you for that. So, yeah, thank
为此感谢您。 所以，是的，谢谢
[Music]
[音乐]
Dr. Pep Gnardas.
Pep Gnardas 博士。
What is it you spent the entirety of
你毕生
decades of your career focusing on
致力于预防心脏病，尤其是在职业生涯的最后几十年里，心脏病
&gt;&gt; prevention of heart disease which is the
是
world right now. You see the heart is
目前全世界排名第一的死因。 你看，心脏是
made up of many parts. So this is
由许多部分组成的。 所以这一点很
important. It's a pump. So it's a
重要。 这是一个泵。 所以它是一块
muscle. So you have diseases of the
肌肉。 所以
muscle and it's rampant these days.
现在肌肉疾病很猖獗。
Cardiomyopathy,
心肌病，
weakness of the muscle. Then you have
肌肉无力。 然后是
the arteries on top of the heart and
心脏上方的动脉，
that's called coronary artery disease.
这种情况被称为冠状动脉疾病。
Diseases of the arteries they block up.
它们阻塞的动脉会引发疾病。
Then you have the valves. The valves
然后就是阀门了。 阀门
tend to get damaged as well. For
也容易损坏。
example, aotic stenosis. And then you
例如，耳道狭窄。 然后
have the peripheral circulation. All the
还有外周循环。 所有
blood vessels that go to your corateeds,
通往你心脏、
your brain, your legs and to all the
大脑、腿部以及
organs of your body. And then you have
身体所有器官的血管。 然后还有
microvascular disease which is the tiny
微血管疾病，也就是微小的
capillaries
毛细血管也
that they become dysfunctional as well.
出现功能障碍。
&gt;&gt; What's a capillary?
什么是毛细血管？
&gt;&gt; Capillary is the branch of the branch of
毛细血管是
the branch.
分支的分支的分支。
&gt;&gt; Okay. So like the tiny little veins
好的。 就像
&gt;&gt; final ones. Yeah. So when they become
最后那些细小的血管一样。 是的。 所以当它们功能
dysfunctional that organ becomes
失调时，该器官也会功能
dysfunctional as well. So cardiology
失调。 因此，心脏病学会
affects all these aspects.
影响所有这些方面。
&gt;&gt; And how long have you been operating on
你从事心脏手术多久了
people's hearts? about 35 years now.
？ 大约35年了。
&gt;&gt; And how many hearts do you think you've
你认为你已经治愈了多少颗心
treated?
？
&gt;&gt; In excess of 30,000.
超过30000。
&gt;&gt; And what what's the age range of those
这些患者的年龄范围是多少
patients?
？   以前
&gt;&gt; They were used to be mostly older people
他们大多是
over 65. Now I would say 50% of them are
65岁以上的老年人。现在，我认为其中一半是
under 65 and 50% are over 65. So the
65岁以下的，一半是65岁以上的。所以
demographics is changing. The younger
人口结构正在发生变化。
people are developing heart disease. So,
年轻人也开始患心脏病。 那么，
the youngest patient you've ever
你治疗过的最年轻的病人是
treated?
？
&gt;&gt; 28.
28.
&gt;&gt; And what what was the predicament in
那么，当时的困境是什么呢
that case?
？
&gt;&gt; He was having a full-blown heart attack.
他当时突发严重心脏病。
So, that means that one of his arteries
所以，这意味着他的一条动脉
was completely clogged up. It had a
完全堵塞了。
blood clot in it. There was no
里面有血栓。
circulation past that artery and
那条动脉没有血液循环，
therefore he was having acute chest
因此他出现了剧烈的
pain, sweating, blood pressure was low.
胸痛、出汗、血压低等症状。
He comes straight to the hospital. I
他直接来到了医院。 我
rushed to the hospital, take him
赶紧赶到医院，直接把他
straight into the kath lab and try to
送到导管室，试图
open up that blockage. And we did open
疏通堵塞的血管。 我们
up that blockage and put a stent in it
疏通了堵塞处，并在其中放置了一个支架，
and got rid of that blockage immediately
立即清除了堵塞物，
to restore that blood flow to the heart
恢复了心肌的血液供应
muscle.
。
&gt;&gt; And at 28, how does one get a heart
28岁怎么会得
attack? You said it was blocked up.
心脏病呢？ 你说它堵塞了。
&gt;&gt; There's a lot of nuance in that. Most
这里面有很多细微差别。 大多数
people don't understand what a heart
人并不了解心脏病
attack is. So, in a nutshell, I'm going
发作是什么。 简而言之，我将
to tell you what it is. When you have a
告诉你它是什么。 动脉内壁形成
plaque, a plaque is a buildup of a
斑块，是指
fibrous material inside the artery
动脉内壁上积聚了一些纤维物质，
and that doesn't cause a heart attack. A
但这不会导致心脏病发作。
heart attack is caused when one of those
当这些斑块中的一个破裂时，就会导致心脏病发作
cracks. Now in this diagram for example,
。 例如，在这张图中，
it's showing that the plaque is closing
它显示斑块正在
up the artery and this will cause
阻塞动脉，这将导致
angina. That means a lack of blood
心绞痛。 这意味着
supply over here. So this patient may
这里血液供应不足。 所以这位患者可能会
complain of chest discomfort or he may
抱怨胸部不适，也可能
not complain of chest discomfort because
不会抱怨胸部不适，因为
remember when you have a blockage like
记住，当出现
this only 20% of the patients actually
这种阻塞时，只有 20% 的患者实际上会
get chest pain.
出现胸痛。
That means that you could have a
这意味着，患者可能存在这样的血管
blockage like this in a patient and you
阻塞，但
may not have any chest discomfort and
可能不会出现任何胸部不适，而
the only way you're going to pick that
发现这种情况的唯一方法
up is by doing a stress test or a
是进行压力测试、
coronary calcium score or some other
冠状动脉钙化评分或其他检查
modality to see whether he has blockage
方法，以确定他是否存在血管阻塞
or not. A heart attack is when a minor
。 心脏病发作是指轻微的血管
blockage which is not causing much flow
阻塞（通常不会造成太大的血流
disturbance suddenly cracks
紊乱）突然破裂，
come that cracks off
破裂后脱落的斑块会形成血栓，
&gt;&gt; and when it cracks open the blood that's
血液流经破裂处时会
going past it sees the crack and wants
试图
to repair it and forms a blood clot on
修复它，并在其上形成血栓
it. So the final thing that shuts down
。 所以，最终导致动脉阻塞的原因
that artery is a blood clot. It's not
是血栓。 导致血管
the plaque that shuts it off, it's a
阻塞的不是斑块，而是
blood clot. So a heart attack is caused
血栓。 所以，心脏病发作是
by a blood clot at the sight of a
由血管
rupture and what causes rupture is
破裂处形成的血栓引起的，而血管破裂的原因是
inflammation.
炎症。
&gt;&gt; Okay. So when people say that heart
好的。 所以当人们说
disease is the number one killer of
心脏病是患病人群的头号杀手时
diseased. Is it that process that's
。 是这个过程
causing it alone or is there a multitude
本身导致了心脏病，还是有很多其他
of processes that lead to heart disease?
过程导致了心脏病？
&gt;&gt; There's a multitude of things that lead
导致
to heart disease. Look,
心脏病的原因有很多。 你看，
&gt;&gt; that was a heart attack. That's right.
那是心脏病发作。 这是正确的。
So, one, you're making plaque. You
所以，第一，你在制造牙菌斑。 你
shouldn't be making plaque.
不应该制造牙菌斑。
A plaque is an inflammatory
斑块是
area inside your arteries. It's reacting
动脉内壁的炎症区域。 它对
to something. And I can go into the
某些事物做出了反应。 我可以深入
nuance of what's actually what's the
探讨身体究竟对什么
body reacting to? What's inflammation?
做出反应吗？ 什么是炎症？
Inflammation is reacting to something.
炎症是对某种刺激的反应。   那
What is that something? And I think it's
是什么？ 我认为，
important for your audience and
对于你的观众和
everybody to know what that something
所有人来说，了解那是什么非常重要
is. Now, you've got this pimple. Think
。 现在，你脸上长了个痘痘。 你可以把
of it as a pimple on the inside of the
它想象成动脉内壁上的一个粉刺
artery.
。
Now, one day when there's enough
总有一天，当
inflammation in your body systemically,
你的身体系统性炎症达到一定程度时，
that pimple is going to crack open just
那个痘痘就会像
like a pimple on the skin breaks open.
皮肤上的痘痘破裂一样破裂。
Now, that artery has this little pimple
现在，这条动脉内壁上有一个小疙瘩，
on the inside and it cracks open and a
它破裂后会
blood clot forms on it and that's a
形成血栓，这就是
heart attack. So, you don't want plaque
心脏病发作。 所以，你不想
formation. You don't want plaque
形成斑块。 你不希望出现斑块
instability which is rupture of that
不稳定（即
plaque and you don't want a blood clot
斑块破裂），也不希望
to form on it. There are factors that
在斑块上形成血栓。
affect each of these processes and all
影响这些过程的因素有很多，而
three processes are going wrong today
如今这三个过程都出现了问题，
and that's why we have so much plaque
这就是为什么我们会出现如此多的斑块
formation and instability of the plaque
形成和斑块不稳定，
which then leads of course to heart
这当然会导致心脏病
attacks and our blood in general. We
发作以及我们整体的血液问题。
have more coagulation issues today than
如今我们面临的凝血问题比以往任何时候都多
we ever did before. Which means our
。 这意味着
blood because of inflammation is more
由于炎症，我们的血液
ready to clot more easily. So we having
更容易凝固。 所以我们拥有了
the perfect triad.
完美的三角关系。
It's the perfect storm. That's why we're
这是一场完美风暴。 这就是为什么我们现在
seeing an epidemic of this. And that's
看到这种疾病呈流行趋势的原因。 这就是
why we're not making a dent in it. Yes,
为什么我们收效甚微的原因。 是的，
you can have a plaque rupture and have a
斑块破裂会导致
heart attack and we put a stent in you.
心脏病发作，我们会为您植入支架。
Okay, that's fine. But what did we do to
好的，没问题。 但是，我们采取了哪些措施来
look at the underlying reason as to why
探究导致
you formed that plaque and why did you
你形成斑块、斑块
rupture it and why was your blood so
破裂以及血液最初为何如此
clotty in the first place that made you
凝结以至于
actually seal off the artery?
堵塞动脉的根本原因呢？
&gt;&gt; Is this an increasing problem?
这个问题是否日益严重？
&gt;&gt; Yes, it's a it's a huge problem because
是的，这是一个大问题，因为
those factors have been identified now
这些因素现在已经被发现，
and that's what we go for in my
而这正是我在
practice. We look for the factors. Why
实践中努力的方向。 我们来寻找这些因素。
did you make this plaque?
你为什么制作这块牌匾？
Why is there so much inflammation in
为什么你体内会有这么多炎症
your body? Inflammation is a reaction to
？ 炎症是对
something foreign. What is that foreign
外界物质的一种反应。 那是什么外国
stuff? What is that abnormal physiology
货？ 你体内究竟存在哪种异常生理现象，
in you that your body is reacting
以至于你的身体正在
against? Cuz that's what inflammation
对其产生反应？ 因为炎症就是炎症
is. And inflammation, of course,
。 当然，炎症也会导致血液凝块的形成，
whenever there's going to be
只要出现
inflammation, there's going to be
炎症，就更
increased tendency to make blood clots.
容易形成血栓。
So, we go in, we chase all these things
所以，我们会进去，在病人身上追踪所有这些情况，
in patients to find out. And that's the
找出原因。 这才是
real prevention.
真正的预防措施。
that 28-year-old that came in um and you
那位28岁的病人来
treated him, was it was that a surgery
就诊，你给他
you did?
做了手术吗？
&gt;&gt; We call it a surgery, but it's not. It's
我们称之为手术，但它不是手术。 这
a it's a angoplasty. So, we go in from
是血管成形术。 所以，我们从
the wrist.
手腕处开始。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
。
&gt;&gt; Or we go in from the groin with a
或者我们从腹股沟插入
catheter and we go into the coronary
导管，进入
artery.
冠状动脉。
&gt;&gt; A catheter being like a tube.
导管就像一根管子。
&gt;&gt; It's a hollow tube. And we put it into
这是一个空心管。 然后我们把它注入
the coronary artery. We shoot the dye
冠状动脉。 我们将染料注入
inside. We can see where the blockage
内部。 我们可以看到堵塞点在哪里
is. And then we thread a tiny wire into
。 然后我们将一根细小的导丝穿过
that artery through the blockage and
堵塞的动脉，
then bring in a balloon and squash the
再放入一个球囊，将血栓挤压
blood clot out of the way. Restore the
出来。 恢复血液
circulation
循环，
and then bring in a stent. A stent is
然后植入支架。 支架就像
like a spring that opens the artery up.
弹簧一样，可以撑开动脉。
We leave the stent inside there. We
我们把支架留在里面。 我们
remove everything else and now you have
移除了其他所有东西，现在
an open artery and you have blood flow
动脉就畅通了，血液可以
going down that artery.
顺着这条动脉流下去。
&gt;&gt; And what had that 28-year-old done to
那位28岁的年轻人究竟做了什么，才会落到需要
end up in your surgery? What were the
你动手术的地步？
decisions that they had made that
他们究竟做出了哪些决定才导致
brought them there?
他们落到这步田地？
&gt;&gt; So, he was number one, he was
所以，他是第一名，他
overweight, but he wasn't just
超重，但他不仅仅是
overweight. The overweight was all in
超重。 他所有的赘肉都堆积在
his belly and he had a fatty liver and
腹部，他患有脂肪肝，而且体内还有
he had what is known as visceral fat. He
内脏脂肪。 他虽然
was not a diabetic, but he was a
不是糖尿病患者，但却是
pre-diabetic.
糖尿病前期患者。
That means he had a lot of insulin in
这意味着他体内有很多胰岛素，
his body and his glucose levels were
血糖水平也
good. So, if you went to his family
很好。 所以，如果你去看他的家庭
doctor, they would say, "Oh, you're not
医生，他们会说：“哦，你不是
a diabetic. your hemoglobin A1C which is
糖尿病患者。你的糖化血红蛋白A1c（一种
a blood test that you do for diabetes is
糖尿病血液检查）
actually okay but actually that patient
其实正常，但实际上这位患者的
had a very high insulin blood level. Now
胰岛素水平非常高。
insulin is a very aogenic molecule. It
胰岛素是一种非常活跃的分子，它会
causes smooth muscle proliferation.
导致平滑肌增生。
Smooth muscle is in the walls of the
平滑肌位于
arteries. It causes vasoc constriction.
动脉壁上，它会导致血管收缩，
It makes your blood more clotty and it
使血液更容易凝结，并
causes inflammation.
引起炎症。
So this patient was a pre-diabetic
所以这位患者是糖尿病前期患者，
and this is very important and this is
这一点非常重要，也正是这一点
what caught my attention because when I
引起了我的注意。因为我
looked at my patients that were coming
观察那些因
in with heart attacks and hardening of
心脏病发作和
the arteries and when I tried to
动脉硬化前来就诊的患者，试图
identify why they doing this none of
找出他们患病的原因，发现
them were diabetics
他们都不是糖尿病患者。
but then I did a glucose tolerance test
但我给他们做了葡萄糖耐量试验，碰巧
tests in my office where you can measure
我的诊室里有这种可以测量
the blood glucose. So I had about 120 of
血糖的仪器，我手头正好有大约120台
them. So I said, "Look, let's just do
。于是我说：“我们
some random testing on these patients
随机抽取一些患者进行测试吧。”结果
and I found that at least half of them
发现…… 至少有一半人
had no diabetes but their glucose
没有糖尿病，但存在葡萄糖
intolerance. That means that the sugars
耐受不良。 这意味着血糖
went up but not enough to make them a
升高了，但还没到患
diabetic but it did go above the normal
糖尿病的程度，不过确实超过了正常
range. We did not have insulin testing
范围。 当时我们还没有胰岛素检测技术
at that time. About 10 years later, we
。 大约 10 年后，我们
started testing insulin in the office.
开始在办公室进行胰岛素测试。
And I bought a machine for this purpose
为此，我在办公室买了一台机器
in my office to measure insulin levels
来测量胰岛素水平，从此
and life was never the same again.
生活发生了翻天覆地的变化。
&gt;&gt; Why?
为什么？
&gt;&gt; Because it's all about insulin when it
因为
comes to the metabolic derangement. So I
代谢紊乱的关键就在于胰岛素。 我
found that these patients the sugars
发现，给这些病人喝葡萄糖水
were going up to 150, 160 after giving
后，他们的血糖会升至 150、160
them a glucose drink.
。
&gt;&gt; Mhm.
嗯。
&gt;&gt; So you say, okay, he's not a diabetic.
所以你会说，好吧，他不是糖尿病患者。
Look, the sugar didn't really go high,
你看，血糖并没有真的升高，
but when you measured the insulin level,
但是当你测量胰岛素水平时，
the insulin was off the roof.
胰岛素水平却飙升到了极高水平。
&gt;&gt; So, when you say this is an insulin
所以，你说这是胰岛素
problem, can you explain this to me?
问题，你能给我解释一下吗？
Like, I have no idea what glucose and
比如，我完全不知道葡萄糖和
insulin are for for any of my listeners
胰岛素是做什么用的，可能我的听众朋友们对
understanding of these these these terms
这些术语
and what they what they do and mean.
及其作用和含义不太了解。
&gt;&gt; It's crucial. Everybody needs to
这至关重要。 每个人都需要
understand the relationship between
了解
sugar, which is glucose, and insulin.
糖（即葡萄糖）和胰岛素之间的关系。
When you consume sugar or glucose, the
当你摄入糖或葡萄糖时，
body has to get rid of that glucose very
身体必须迅速将葡萄糖
quickly from the bloodstream because
从血液中清除出去，因为
glucose actually is toxic inside the
葡萄糖在血液中实际上是有毒的
bloodstream. Even though it is what the
。 虽然糖是
body uses for energy in the bloodstream,
人体血液中能量的来源，但
it glycates all the blood vessels and
它会使所有血管、
the walls and the components in blood
血管壁以及血液成分
and hemoglobin as well glycates it. That
和血红蛋白发生糖化。 这
means a glucose attaches itself to that
意味着一个葡萄糖分子会附着在该
molecule. So now that molecule can't
分子上。 所以现在这个分子无法
work properly. That is why the higher
正常工作了。 这就是为什么
your blood glucose,
血糖越高，
all your chemicals don't work well, your
你体内的所有化学物质都无法正常运作，你的
enzymes don't work well, your hormones
酶无法正常运作，你的激素
don't work well, nothing works well, and
无法正常运作，一切都无法正常运作，
you age prematurely because you're
你会因为糖化作用而过早衰老
getting glycation. Glyca, a glycated
。 糖基化
molecule can't work normally. It doesn't
分子（Glyca）无法正常发挥作用。 它无法
function normally.
正常工作。
&gt;&gt; So when you consume the glucose, the
所以当你摄入葡萄糖时，
glucose has to come out of the
葡萄糖必须从
bloodstream. And how does the body do
血液中释放出来。 人体是如何做到这一点的呢
it? It sends a message to the pancreas.
？ 它会向胰腺发送信息。
The pancreas says, "Aha, I'll make some
胰腺说：“啊哈，我来制造一些
insulin." It pours insulin into the
胰岛素。” 它将胰岛素注入
bloodstream. Insulin comes into the
血液。 胰岛素进入
bloodstream, pushes the glucose into the
血液，推动葡萄糖进入
cells. And where does it pushing it?
细胞。 它要把它推向哪里？
Into the liver, into the muscles, into
进入肝脏，进入肌肉，进入
every cell in the body. Insulin will
身体的每一个细胞。 胰岛素会将
push glucose out. Now, how much insulin
葡萄糖排出体外。 现在的问题是，需要多少胰岛素？
If I'm eating every 3 hours and I'm
如果我每隔3小时进食一次，并且
consuming glucose or I'm consuming
摄入的是葡萄糖、
starchy foods or I'm consuming
淀粉类食物或
carbohydrates. Now watch where I'm going
碳水化合物。 现在注意我的下一步动作，
with this because you're already
因为你已经
beginning to know where I'm going with
开始知道我的下一步动作了
this. I'm consuming glucose and carbs
。 我
every 2 three hours. I'm stimulating my
每隔两三个小时就要摄入葡萄糖和碳水化合物。 我正在刺激
pancreas. I'm stimulating my insulin. My
胰腺。 我正在刺激胰岛素分泌。 我的
insulin goes up, it comes down. But
胰岛素水平时而升高，时而降低。 但
before it even gets a chance to come
它还没来得及
down, it goes up again.
落下来，就又升起来了。
So the repeated consumption of and
因此，反复和
frequent consumption of glucose is
频繁地摄入葡萄糖会
causing my insulin to stay high because
导致我的胰岛素水平居高不下，因为
insulin stays a little bit longer in the
胰岛素在血液中停留的时间
bloodstream than the glucose. The
比葡萄糖稍长一些。
glucose will come down in about 2 to 3
血糖会在 2 到 3
hours but the insulin stays higher for
小时内下降，但胰岛素水平会在 4 小时内保持较高水平
about 4 hours. Now what happens is that
。 接下来发生的是，
you continue this lifestyle for a few
你继续这种生活方式
years.
几年。
Now the body because these are all
现在，因为这些都是
hormones will say well you know it's I'm
激素，身体会说，你知道，我现在
going to need to make more insulin now
需要产生更多的胰岛素，于是
you become insulin resistant. Any
你就出现了胰岛素抵抗。 任何
hormone that stays in your body for a
激素如果在体内停留时间
long time the body becomes immune to it.
过长，身体都会对其产生耐药性。
So the next time I eat the sugar I'm
所以下次我吃糖的时候，就
going to have to make more insulin to
需要分泌更多的胰岛素才能
produce the same effect. That is called
产生同样的效果。 这叫做
insulin resistance. So now you got this
胰岛素抵抗。 所以现在你有了这样一个
patient who's been eating carbs,
病人，他一直在吃碳水化合物、
sugar,
糖和
processed foods. What does that mean?
加工食品。 这意味着什么？
Processed foods that means foods that
加工食品是指能
are quickly absorbed into the
迅速被
bloodstream. Processed foods, these are
血液吸收的食品。 加工食品，这些
products without fiber. So the
产品不含膳食纤维。 所以
absorption is very quick. So the poor
吸收速度非常快。 所以可怜的
pancreas has to react just like that.
胰腺只能做出这样的反应。
Produces a whole bunch of insulin. And
产生大量胰岛素。
then the frequent eating and the
频繁进食和
frequent consumption makes you insulin
频繁摄入会导致胰岛素
resistance. So now you produce a whole
抵抗。 所以现在你会产生
bunch of insulin in order to bring that
大量的胰岛素来
sugar level down. So then you say, okay,
降低血糖水平。 所以你就说，好吧，
well it doesn't matter because insul the
这没关系，因为
insulin is bringing the sugar level
胰岛素会降低血糖水平
down. So what's the harm done? Because
。 那么，这会造成什么损害呢？ 因为
your A1C is still good. You're not a
你的糖化血红蛋白A1C值仍然良好。 你不是
diabetic. No, but it's that background
糖尿病患者。 不，正是体内过高的
high insulin that is destroying your
胰岛素水平破坏了你的
metabolism.
新陈代谢。
It's that high insulin level in the
这是高胰岛素水平在
background. So insulin pushes glucose
作祟。 所以胰岛素会将葡萄糖推
into the liver and you develop a fatty
入肝脏，从而导致脂肪
liver.
肝。
It pushes the calories into production
它会将热量转化为
of new fats around your viscera. The
内脏周围新脂肪的生成。
viscera means in your belly around your
内脏指的是胰腺周围的腹部区域，也
pancreas you get visceral fat. Now this
就是内脏脂肪。 这种
fat is produced from glucose. It's a
脂肪是由葡萄糖转化而来的。 这是
different kind of fat. Look if I gave
另一种脂肪。 听着，如果我
you a high calorie diet right now of all
现在给你一份高热量、各种食物的饮食计划，
sorts of foods you put on weight
你会
everywhere. Okay?
全身都长胖。 好的？
But if I give you glucose, you put it on
但如果我给你注射葡萄糖，它
mostly in your stomach and your stomach
主要会沉积在你的胃里，你的胃
will protrude and that's called visceral
就会凸出来，这就是所谓的内脏
fat. It's on the inside. You can't pinch
脂肪。 它在里面。 你捏不起来
it. It's on the inside
它。 它位于
&gt;&gt; around your organs
你体内器官
&gt;&gt; around the organs. This is very
周围。 这是非常
detrimental fat. And that's the epidemic
有害的脂肪。 这就是
that we have today. And that's a direct
我们今天面临的疫情。 这是
result of eating, you know, starchy
摄入淀粉类
glucose, carbohydrates, which creates
葡萄糖、碳水化合物的直接结果，这些物质会产生
insulin, which creates this downstream
胰岛素，从而
effect on
对
&gt;&gt; wrong foods and eating too frequently.
不健康的食物和进食过于频繁产生连锁反应。
&gt;&gt; Too frequently. Okay?
太频繁了。 好的？
&gt;&gt; Because remember, it's also the
因为记住，
frequency of eating because before that
进食频率也很重要，因为只有这样，
insulin gets a chance to come down.
胰岛素才有机会下降。
You're already popping yourself with
你已经摄入了
more food and hence you develop insulin
过多的食物，因此会产生胰岛素
resistance. You get a very high insulin.
抵抗。 你的胰岛素水平会非常高。
It takes this much insulin now just to
现在需要这么多胰岛素才能
bring that sugar level down. And then
把血糖降下来。 然后有
the one day when you cannot control that
一天，你无法控制
sugar now that sugar will go out and now
血糖，血糖就会飙升，
your doctor will say you're a diabetic
你的医生会说你是糖尿病患者，
but by that time you've already had 10
但到那时你已经患有
years of hyperinsulinemia.
高胰岛素血症 10 年了。
So what happens if by the time you make
那么，如果等到
a diagnosis of diabetes to say well now
确诊糖尿病时，发现
your sugar is really high it is high
血糖很高，这是
because your body has not had the
因为你的身体没有
ability to keep it down. Why? Because
能力控制血糖，那会发生什么呢？ 为什么？ 因为
even that high insulin could not keep
即使胰岛素水平很高，也无法
your sugar level down. You became a
降低你的血糖水平。 你患上了
diabetic. You lost that whole
糖尿病。 你错失了整个
opportunity of prevention. It's those 10
预防的机会。 就是那
years. Look, by the time you're a
十年。 你看，等你患上
diabetic and you come and see Dr. Jay in
糖尿病，到杰伊医生的
his cardiac clinic, you already have
心脏诊所就诊时，你已经患有
coronary artery disease. Like that
冠状动脉疾病了。 就像那位
28-year-old, that 28-year-old didn't
28岁的年轻人一样，那位28岁的年轻人也没有
have diabetes. He already has coronary
糖尿病。 他已经患有
artery disease. By the time you are
冠状动脉疾病。 当你被
diagnosed as having diabetes, you
确诊患有糖尿病时，你
already have coronary artery disease. We
已经患有冠状动脉疾病了。 我们
have a great opportunity here to
现在有一个很好的机会，可以
with insulin levels very early on. But
很早开始对这些患者进行胰岛素水平筛查。 但
most doctors don't have the ability or
大多数医生没有能力或
knowledge to do the insulin level
知识进行胰岛素水平
testing, but it should be done.
检测，但应该进行这项检测。   像
&gt;&gt; In someone like me, I'm 33 years old
我这样的人，今年已经33岁了
now. When does the damage begin?
。 损害何时开始？
&gt;&gt; It starts right now. It starts right
现在就开始。
now. As soon as you around 30, you're
现在就开始。 大概到了30岁左右，你
already starting to have trouble. You
就开始遇到一些问题了。 你
have to But you know, this is what I do.
必须这么做。但是你知道，这就是我所做的。
I look at that patient walking into my
我看着走进我
room and if I see that he's got a belly
房间的病人，如果我看到他肚子
sticking out, I already know he's
凸出来，我就知道他
probably got insulin resistance because
可能患有胰岛素抵抗，因为
all the fat is in here. Because the fat
所有的脂肪都在这里。 因为
that's in the stomach, sideways, he
肚子上的脂肪堆积在两侧，让他
looks terrible. From the back, he looks
看起来很糟糕。 从后面看，他看起来
great. His waist is increased.
很棒。 他的腰围增加了。
&gt;&gt; Mhm. He doesn't have all the fat
嗯。 他身上其他部位并不是到处都是脂肪
everywhere else in his body. That's the
。 这是高
hyperinsulinemia.
胰岛素血症患者的表型。
That same person goes on a cruise, he'll
同一个人如果去坐游轮，
come back 5 to 10 pounds more because
回来后体重会增加 5 到 10 磅，因为
he's got so much insulin in his body.
他体内有很多胰岛素。
Insulin is a storage molecule. Puts
胰岛素是一种储存分子。 把
everything away. And it's very hard for
所有东西都收起来。
him to lose weight.
他减肥非常困难。
&gt;&gt; Why is it harder? you the only thing
为什么会更难？ 唯一
that will make you lose that fat very
能让你快速减掉脂肪的方法
quickly is to change your diet of course
当然是改变饮食习惯，
but you have to do fasting because
但你必须进行禁食，因为
fasting brings your insulin level. See
禁食会降低你的胰岛素水平。
this is where fasting comes in. So what
这就是禁食的作用所在。那么，
does fasting do?
禁食究竟有什么作用呢？
&gt;&gt; Do you mean fasting or a calorie
您指的是禁食还是热量
deficit? Is it or is it the same thing
缺口？
in your view?
在你看来，它们是同一回事吗？
&gt;&gt; No, they're not the same thing. They are
不，它们不是一回事。 它们
not the same thing. You see when you
不是一回事。 你看，当你
don't eat your insulin levels come down
不进食时，你的胰岛素水平就会下降，
because you not stimulating your
因为你的胰腺不再受到刺激
pancreas anymore. So you want to bring
。 所以你想
your insulin levels down. the best thing
降低胰岛素水平。
you can do in the world is to do fasting
世界上你能做的最好的事情就是禁食，
because there's no look if I just simply
因为如果你只是简单地
cut down on my calories
减少卡路里摄入，
then there's a different physiology
那么身体就会发生不同的生理变化。当你
and when you fast there's a totally
禁食时，身体会发生完全
different physiology when you cut down
不同的生理变化。当你减少
on calories the body senses that this
卡路里摄入时，身体会感知到这种
caloric deficit your metabolic rate
热量缺口，你的新陈代谢率
changes actually slows down and the body
实际上会减慢，身体
will start breaking down everything
会开始分解所有物质，
included. So you lose fat and you also
包括肌肉。 所以你减掉的是脂肪，同时也会
lose muscles. On the other hand, when
减掉肌肉。 另一方面，
you're fasting, it's a different
禁食时，
physiology.
生理反应则有所不同。
Fasting is I've put on fat. Now I'm
禁食让我长胖了。 现在我
going to take it out of the bank. Now
要去银行取钱。 现在我可以从我的
to pull out my calories and use it now.
卡路里储备中取出并使用它们了。
And you start burning the fat. So in the
然后你就开始燃烧脂肪。 因此，在
first 12 hours of a fast, you take out
禁食的前 12 个小时里，你会从肌肉和肝脏中清除
all the glucose in the form of glycogen
所有以糖原形式存在的葡萄糖
from your muscles and your liver. After
。
12 hours, you start pulling the fat out.
12小时后，开始抽出脂肪。
And the first place the fat comes out of
脂肪最先从
is going to be visceral fat. That is why
内脏脂肪中释放出来。 这就是为什么
fasting benefits you so much because it
禁食对你如此有益的原因，因为它能
gets rid of that worst fat. The fat that
去除最顽固的脂肪。 这种脂肪
is very inflammatory. You see, if I did
具有很强的炎症性。 你看，如果我对
a biopsy of your visceral fat versus a
你的内脏脂肪进行活检，再
biopsy of let's say a fat form on your
对你臀部的脂肪组织进行活检
buttock,
，这
&gt;&gt; two different types of fat. One is full
两种脂肪是不同的类型。 其中一种
of inflammatory molecules. The other one
富含炎症分子。 另一种则
is not full of inflammatory molecules.
不含炎症分子。
One is producing interlucan 6 and tumor
其中一种脂肪组织能产生白细胞介素-6和肿瘤
necrosis factor and this other fat is
坏死因子，而另一种脂肪组织则
not. These are two different fat
不能。 这是两种不同的脂肪
stoages.
储存方式。
Visceral fat is very toxic. It's very
内脏脂肪毒性很强。 它具有很强的
inflammatory. And that is why patients
煽动性。 这就是为什么
who have visceral fat make all these
内脏脂肪患者会产生所有这些
molecules. So when I do the blood test I
分子的原因。 所以当我做血液检查时，我
see that oh you've got so much
发现你体内有很多
inflammation. You've got interlucan 6 is
炎症。 你的白细胞介素-6水平
high tumor necrosis factor is high. Your
高，肿瘤坏死因子水平也高。 您的
CRP is running high. And one of the
C反应蛋白水平偏高。
reasons for this is not just leaky gut
造成这种情况的原因之一不仅是肠漏症
and other things that I look at, but in
和其他一些我观察到的问题，而且在
your case is also because you have a lot
你的情况下，还因为你有很多
of ectopic fat. Ectopic fat. Ectopic fat
异位脂肪。 异位脂肪。
is now we realizing is not just only
我们现在意识到，异位脂肪不仅存在于
around the liver and around your
肝脏和
pancreas, it's also around your heart.
胰腺周围，也存在于心脏周围。
So when we look at the coronary arteries
所以，当我们观察冠状动脉时
and we see all those fat around the
，会看到冠状动脉周围有很多脂肪
coronary arteries, you had a very nice
，你
diagram right there and you can see that
刚才看到的图表就很好，你可以看到
around each artery
每条动脉周围
there's that yellowess that yellow is
都有黄色，那些黄色都是
all plaque
斑块
fat. There's fat around that and it's
脂肪。 周围有脂肪，而且正在
plaque forming. It's plaque forming. It
形成斑块。 它正在形成斑块。 它会
stimulates plaque. It's inflammatory.
刺激牙菌斑的形成。 它具有煽动性。
And now we can do CT scans that will
现在我们还可以进行CT扫描，从而
actually detect how much inflammation is
检测出
in the fat around the arteries as well.
动脉周围脂肪的炎症程度。
Ectopic fat is in the around the
异位脂肪位于
coronary arteries. It's in your liver
冠状动脉周围。 它存在于你的肝脏
and in your pancreas and it is very
和胰腺中，而且会引起严重的
inflammatory.
炎症。
&gt;&gt; On this point of fasting, so if you have
关于禁食这一点，如果你遇到体型比较胖，
bit more of that protruding belly fat,
腹部脂肪比较突出的人，
you said that fasting is a much better
你说禁食
approach than just sort of a calorie
比单纯
restriction. was looking at some studies
限制卡路里摄入要好得多。 我查阅了一些研究，这些
that said research shows that calorie
研究表明，
deficits of any kind can reduce fiscal
任何形式的热量缺口都可以减少体内
fat, but fasting will give it an edge
脂肪，但禁食会更有优势，
because of the insulin sensitivity stuff
因为你也提到了胰岛素敏感性方面的问题
that you talked about as well. What kind
。
of fast should one be doing? Because
应该进行哪种类型的禁食？ 因为
these fasts. People do these 40-day
这些斋戒方式有很多不同的名称。 人们会进行为期 40 天的
water fasts and they do intermittent
断食（只喝水），也会进行间歇性
fasting.
断食。
&gt;&gt; It's a great question. So, there are
这是一个很好的问题。 因此，
depending on your goal on what you want
根据你希望为
for that particular patient. So if a
特定患者达到的目标，禁食有很多种不同的类型。 所以，如果
patient is just simply looking to reduce
病人只是想减少
his visceral fat then I start with 1212
内脏脂肪，那么我会从 1212 开始，
which means 12 hours you don't eat
这意味着 12 小时内什么都不吃
anything. You just drink liquids with no
。 你只需要喝不含
calories in it and then 12 hours is your
卡路里的液体，然后12小时是你的
feeding period. We start with that and
进食期。 我们先这样做，然后持续
we do that for about 2 to 3 weeks. Then
大约 2 到 3 周。 然后
we quickly move to 186.
我们迅速过渡到186。186
186 means 6 hours you get to eat. 18
意味着你有6个小时的吃饭时间。  18
hours. It's only
小时。 只有
water, black tea, black coffee, green
水、红茶、黑咖啡、
tea, no calories. 186.
绿茶，不含卡路里。  186.
186. And then that's one type of
186. 那就是一种
fasting. Now, if a patient is very
禁食方式。 如果一位病人严重
overweight, a patient has diabetes and
超重，患有糖尿病，而
your goal is to reverse the diabetes,
你的目标是逆转糖尿病，
the patient needs to lose 60 pounds,
病人需要减掉 60 磅，
then those patients have a special type
那么这些病人就有了特殊
of need. For them, I will take them to a
的需求。 为了他们，我每周会带他们进行
48 hour fast once a week. Sometimes I'll
一次 48 小时的禁食。 有时我会
go to a three-day water fast every 9
每隔9天进行一次为期3天的断食（只喝水）
days.
。
Every 9 days, you will do OMAD. OMAD
每隔9天，你将进行一次一日一餐（OMAD）。  OMAD
means one meal a day only, every day for
指的是每天只吃一顿饭，连续吃
9 days. And then you're going to give me
9 天。 然后你要让我进行为期
a three-day water fast.
三天的断食（只喝水）。
&gt;&gt; Is the same advice applicable to women?
同样的建议也适用于女性吗？
because obviously they're contending
因为很明显，她们要应对
with a variety of hormone fluctuations
各种激素波动
and estrogen and I know that the the
和雌激素，而且我知道
female body responds differently to
女性的身体对
these kinds of stresses like fasts.
禁食等这类压力的反应与男性不同。
&gt;&gt; I've been asked that question so many
我也经常被病人问到这个问题
times from patients as well. Most of the
。 大多数
women can actually handle it. The only
女性其实都能应付。 只有
trying to become pregnant or or they
正在备孕、
have um or they're already pregnant. I I
已经怀孕的女性才不能这样做。 我
I think that women are not that
认为，在禁食计划方面，女性与男性并没有太大
different when it comes to the fasting
区别
programs. So, in my experience, I've
。 所以，根据我的经验，我
been able to get women to fast. I just
能够让女性禁食。 我刚刚
finished a fast on one lady just now for
结束了一位女士为期
72 days. 72 days. She was terribly
72天的禁食疗程。  72天。 她严重
overweight. She had diabetes. She had
超重。 她患有糖尿病。 她患有
hypertension. She had hyper lipidmia.
高血压。 她患有高脂血症。
She was having hip replacements, knee
她做过髋关节置换手术、膝关节
replacements, joint problems. She had
置换手术，还有关节问题。 她有
skin problems. And we fasted her for 72
皮肤问题。 我们让她禁食了72
days.
天。
&gt;&gt; What did she have in those 72 days in
在那72天里，她喝了哪些
terms of drinks, electrolytes, coffee?
饮料、电解质饮料和咖啡？
What was she?
她是什么人？
&gt;&gt; Great question. So she would have black
问得好。 所以她会喝
tea, black coffee, water, and in the
红茶、黑咖啡和水，
water once a day I tell her to put some
我每天会告诉她往水里加一次
electrolytes in there. So there's a
电解质。 所以有一种
electrolyte called element or sometimes
叫做元素的电解质，或者有时候
I just tell them to go buy some Celtic
我会告诉他们去买一些凯尔特
salt and put half a teaspoon in there
盐，放半茶匙进去，
and once a day you take that. If you get
每天服用一次。 如果你感到
cravings and you feel really really
饥饿难耐
hungry, take some MCT oil, a teaspoon,
，可以取一茶匙MCT油，
and put it in your water and you can
加入水中
drink that as well. I
饮用。 我
&gt;&gt; think it's worth saying that probably
认为有必要提醒各位，最好
you shouldn't try this at home, ladies
不要在家尝试这种方法，
and gentlemen, because obviously medical
因为显然医疗
supervision is critical here. But in the
监督至关重要。 但就
case of that lady, what was the before
那位女士而言，她
and after of that 72-day fast? So,
禁食 72 天前后的情况如何呢？ 所以，
diabetes gone, blood pressure
糖尿病消失了，血压
normalized,
恢复正常，
weight loss, tremendous weight loss. I
体重减轻了，而且体重大幅减轻。 我的
mean, I think she lost about 55 60 lbs.
意思是，我觉得她减掉了大约 55 到 60 磅。
Wow.
哇。
&gt;&gt; Okay. And not only did she lose all that
好的。 她不仅减掉了所有
weight, yes, all that weight from her
体重，是的，她肚子上的赘肉全都
belly was gone, but even her face under
消失了，就连腋下的脸也瘦了
the arms. So, when you lose weight in a
。 所以，通过
fasting program, it's very different
禁食减肥与通过
restricting calories. you actually
限制卡路里摄入减肥截然不同。 你实际上是
retract your your skin. So you get real
在收缩你的皮肤。 所以
changes in your entire body. These
你的整个身体都会发生真正的变化。
patient I had one patient that fasted
我曾有一位病人，
for 183 days under supervision. Okay. So
在监督下禁食了 183 天。 好的。 所以
he went from 400 lb to 210 lb. And when
他的体重从 400 磅减到了 210 磅。当
he walked into the office, you would not
他走进办公室时，你根本
recognize that he's just lost all this
看不出他减掉了这么多
weight because he did not look like skin
体重，因为他看起来不像
on top of bones and then having to have
皮包骨头，也不像需要
surgery to remove all that excess skin.
做手术切除多余皮肤的样子。
Fasting is a totally different
禁食是一种完全不同的
physiology.
生理反应。
In fasting, you you you you the body is
禁食期间，你的身体会
doing a whole lot of things that are
发生很多与平时截然不同的事情
very different. And we can go into the
。 我们还可以深入探讨
physiology of fasting because that's
禁食的生理机制，因为这非常
fascinating. It's a physiology that has
有趣。 这是
not been used by us. We've lost it. So
我们以前从未用过的生理学原理。 我们把它弄丢了。 所以，
one of the things about modern living,
现代生活带来的一个问题是
modern living, we have lost this
，我们已经失去了
physiology of fasting. First of all, why
禁食的生理机能。 首先，
do we still have that physiology in us
我们之所以还保留着这种生理机能，
is because it's supposed to serve a
是因为它原本是有其
purpose because we're supposed to be
作用的，因为我们原本应该有
fasting and feasting, but now we're only
禁食和盛宴的交替，但现在我们只顾着
feasting all the time and we're not
盛宴，却不再
fasting.
禁食了。
In order to go back to normal, you
要想恢复正常，你
should be fasting. Fasting is supposed
应该禁食。 禁食应该
to be a normal part of your existence.
是你正常生活的一部分。
That's the way you were designed. Not
你生来如此。 不是我们
a millisecond in the total existence of
在人类存在的最后一毫秒内所过的这种现代工业化生活方式
the human race. We've changed our
。 我们的
lifestyle so much. Modern man has. But
生活方式发生了很大的变化。 现代人拥有。 但是
our genetics and our physiology has
我们的基因和生理机能却
lagged behind. We were supposed to use
落后了。 我们原本应该将
fasting and feasting as part of our
禁食和盛宴作为我们
normal program, as our normal
正常作息的一部分，作为我们正常的
physiology. That's why we still have it.
生理规律。 这就是我们至今仍保留它的原因。
That is why after 12 hours you start
这就是为什么 12 小时后
making some more ketones in your body
你的体内会开始产生更多酮体，
and the ketones come from fat. You're
而这些酮体来源于脂肪。 你正在把
moving that fat out of storage.
脂肪从储存库中取出来。
&gt;&gt; What is a ketone?
什么是酮？
&gt;&gt; Ah ketones. So ketones are a energy
啊，酮类化合物。 酮体是
molecule produced by the liver. How does
肝脏产生的一种能量分子。
it make it? It makes it from fat. So the
它是如何实现的？ 它由脂肪制成。 所以
fat gets liberalized. And by the way the
脂肪的管制就放宽了。 顺便说一句，
fats only start moving when your insulin
只有当你的胰岛素水平下降时，脂肪才会开始移动
levels are down. So because of fasting
。 由于空腹，
your insulin levels are really low now.
你现在的胰岛素水平非常低。
Okay? Because you've been fasting right?
好的？ 因为你一直在禁食，对吧？
So now the fats start dissolving. So you
现在脂肪开始溶解了。 这样就能
get free fatty acids. The free fatty
得到游离脂肪酸。 游离脂肪酸
acids float into the bloodstream. Free
会进入血液。 游离
fatty acids are fat products. They float
脂肪酸是脂肪产物。 它们会
into the bloodstream. They go to your
进入血液。 它们会进入你的
liver. Your liver converts those into
肝脏。 你的肝脏会将这些物质转化为
ketones. Now ketones are an energy
酮体。 酮体是
source of the body, an alternative
人体的一种能量来源，是
source to glucose. So in general terms,
葡萄糖的替代来源。 所以总的来说，
you are either going to be running on
要么你依靠
glucose and glucose metabolism or you're
葡萄糖和葡萄糖代谢供能，要么你依靠
running on ketones. Okay? And so ketones
酮体供能。 好的？ 因此，酮体
basically show up in the when glucose
基本上会在葡萄糖不存在的时候出现
isn't around.
。
&gt;&gt; That's absolutely right. So ketones and
完全正确。 所以酮类
ketones are actually a cleaner fuel for
物质实际上是人体更清洁的燃料
the body. And in terms of producing
。 就新陈代谢
reactive oxygen species in the
中活性氧的产生而言
metabolism, the way your mitochondria
，由于线粒体的
work, you actually produce less reactive
工作方式，实际上产生的活性
oxygen species, which is damaging to
氧较少，而
your physiology when you're in ketones.
当处于酮体状态时，活性氧会对你的生理机能造成损害。
And ketones are signaling molecules that
酮体是信号分子，它
also change your physiology in a number
还能以多种方式改变你的生理机能
of ways. Number one, it causes the
。 第一，它能促进
factor that occurs under ketogenesis.
酮体生成过程中产生的脑源性神经营养因子的产生。
Brain derived neurotropic factor which
脑源性神经营养因子
means that you become smarter, you're
意味着你会变得更聪明，你的
growing new cells, your reflexes are
新细胞会生长，你的反应会
better, your visual acuity is better.
更好，你的视力会更好。
Why? Because nature wants you to become
为什么？ 因为大自然希望你成为
a better specimen so you can go out and
更优秀的个体，这样你才能出去
get your next kill. So, why don't we all
猎取下一个猎物。 既然酮症这么神奇，为什么我们不都一直
just stay in a state of ketosis then if
保持酮症状态呢
it's so miraculous?
？
&gt;&gt; Well, that's a great question. You don't
这是一个很好的问题。 你不想一直处于
want to be in ketosis all the time
酮症状态，
because that's not what ketosis what
因为酮症状态并非
what our physiology was made for because
我们生理机能的本意，
then you'll just be burning fats,
否则你就会一直燃烧脂肪、
burning fats, burning fats all the time.
燃烧脂肪、燃烧脂肪。
And that's not a good state to be in
而且，长期处于这种状态也不好
constantly either. So, you want to be
。 所以，你想
able to do both. You're supposed to get
两者兼顾。 你应该会收到
your current account and your deposit
你的活期账户和存款
account. You're supposed to work with
账户。 你应该和
both of them. That's the normal
他们两个都合作。 这是正常的
physiology. So not only brain derived
生理反应。 因此，不仅脑源性
neurotropic factor increases but also
神经营养因子增加，
stem cells. Stem cells are amazing.
干细胞也增加。 干细胞真是太神奇了。
And in my patients of course I see that
当然，在我的病人身上，我看到了什么
&gt;&gt; what what is a stem cell?
是干细胞？
&gt;&gt; Stem cells. So stem cells are we all
干细胞。 所以，我们每个人
have stem cells and we all still make
都有干细胞，而且我们仍然会产生
stem cells and they are produced by the
干细胞，干细胞是由
bone marrow. These are pur potent cells.
骨髓产生的。 这些是极具活力的细胞。
Cells made that will then go out and
产生的细胞随后会分化
become whatever they need to become. So
成它们需要成为的任何形态。 所以
they can go out into your circulation,
它们可以进入血液循环，
become a muscle cell, they can become a
变成肌肉细胞、
retinal cell, a skin cell. They can
视网膜细胞、皮肤细胞。 它们可以
transform into anything. So what happens
变成任何东西。 所以，
is that when you break your fast Mhm.
当你结束斋戒的时候，就会发生这种情况。嗯。
you get a surge of stem cells coming out
你的骨髓会涌出大量干细胞
of your bone marrow. Some of them become
。 其中一些会分化成
immunocytes. That is why we know that
免疫细胞。 这就是为什么我们知道
fasting also boosts your immunity.
禁食也能增强免疫力。
People who fast get less infections, get
快速进食的人感染病毒的几率更低，
less sore throats and coughs and colds
喉咙痛、咳嗽、感冒
and the viruses that are going around.
以及其他流行病毒的症状也会减少。
The immunity is better. The stem cells
免疫力有所提高。
are not I'm particularly interested in
我对干细胞并不特别感兴趣，
the stem cells because of a thing called
因为有一种叫做
the progenitor cells, endothelial
祖细胞的东西，即内皮祖
progenitor cells. Progentor cells are
细胞。 祖细胞就是
you see you're always hurting your blood
你一直在损伤的
vessels the lining of the blood vessels
血管，血管内壁
have to be constantly repaired and they
需要不断修复，而
they are repaired by the progentor
修复血管内壁的正是祖
cells. When you do intermittent fasting
细胞。 间歇性禁食
and timerestricted feeding you will
和限时进食会促进
produce more and this has been shown in
更多祖细胞的产生，许多研究已经证明这一点，
and these progentor cells go and repair
这些祖细胞会修复
your blood vessels. So I do what why am
血管。 那我为什么会对
I interested in this? Because I'm a
这个感兴趣呢？ 因为我是一名
vascular doctor, I want my blood vessels
血管科医生，我希望我的血管
to constantly be repairing themselves
能够不断自我修复，以应对
from the damage that we do in day-to-day
我们在日常生活中造成的损伤
life. So stem cell mobilization, brain
。 所以，干细胞动员、脑
derived neurotropic factor, growth
源性神经营养因子、
hormone, you make more growth hormone in
生长激素，禁食期间会产生更多生长激素
fasting.
。
So when should you exercise when you're
那么，禁食期间应该何时锻炼呢
fasting? At the peak of your fast. So,
？ 在禁食的高峰期。 所以，
if I'm going to break my fast at 6:00
如果我要在下午 6 点结束禁食
p.m., I tell patients to go out to the
，我会告诉病人
gym at 4:00 in the afternoon.
下午 4 点去健身房。
But I said, "But doc, how can I do
但我说：“可是医生，我该怎么做呢
that?" You will find that you will put
？” 你会发现，由于生长激素水平较高，你的
on more muscle and you'll retain more
肌肉会增长更多，而且肌肉也会保持得更好
growth hormone. The fastest way and the
。 提高生长激素分泌最快、
best way to actually increase your
最好的方法
growth hormone production is to do
是进行
intermittent fasting.
间歇性禁食。
&gt;&gt; When I sat with um Dr. Stacy Sims, who
我和斯泰西·西姆斯博士坐在一起，她
does a lot lot of um work on women's
对女性
physiology and women's performance. One
生理和女性表现做了很多研究。
of the things she said to me is that if
她跟我说的其中一件事是，如果
a woman in particular
一个女人
tries to do a workout fasted, the body
空腹锻炼，身体
will break down the muscle in a woman
就会分解女性的肌肉，
because she said a woman's body is much
因为她说女性的身体更像
more the hippamus. It's much more
髋关节。 它对
sensitive to changes in a woman's
女性
glucose levels because it's trying to
血糖水平的变化更加敏感，因为它要
defend against, you know, pregnancy and,
抵御怀孕以及
you know, all these kinds of things. So
所有这些情况。 所以，
it shuts down the menstrual cycle if
如果血液中葡萄糖不足，就会停止月经周期。
and and so she said for women in
因此，她特别指出，女性在
eat something before you work out or it
锻炼前一定要吃点东西，否则
will your body will take from the muscle
身体会从肌肉中吸收能量，这
and it will definitely won't the body's
肯定会对身体造成伤害，因为身体对此
very sensitive. It won't want to to help
非常敏感。 如果体内葡萄糖能量不足，它就不会帮助
you build muscle if there's not enough
你构建肌肉
glucose energy in the body. She said for
。 她说，对于
men it's slightly different because
男人来说情况略有不同，因为
we're a little bit more robust and we
我们身体更强壮一些，而且我们天生就
were meant to hunt. So if we were
适合狩猎。 所以，如果我们处于
fasted, our body is, you know, designed
禁食状态，我们的身体会想方设法
to kind of keep up its normal processes
维持正常的生理过程，
to help us complete a hunt, per se. So I
以帮助我们完成狩猎。 所以我
guess I throw this question out to you
想问问大家
about about women exercise and fasting.
关于女性运动和禁食的问题。
&gt;&gt; Yeah, I think that's a great
是的，我觉得这是一个非常好的
observation. So again is what kind of
观察。 那么，
exercise is the woman doing? You see,
这位女士究竟在进行哪种类型的运动呢？ 你看，
now there's two kinds of basic
现在有两种基本
exercises. One is aerobic activity
练习。 一种是有氧运动
&gt;&gt; and one is uh resistance exercises. And
，一种是阻力训练。
you can also throw into that
你还可以加入
highintensity interval training. Mhm. So
高强度间歇训练。 嗯。 所以，
when it comes to the training that I'm
说到我
talking about in a fasting state, I like
所说的空腹状态下的训练，我喜欢
resistance training. So in resistance
阻力训练。 所以在阻力
training, that glucose issue is not
训练中，血糖问题不会
going to become a problem. Now, if
成为问题。 现在，如果
you're going to put that female patient
你要让那位女病人
on a treadmill and make her run for a
上跑步机，让她长时间跑步
long period of time, let's say you're
，比如说，你要让
going to make her run for 40 minutes on
她在跑步机上跑 40 分钟
the treadmill. I think that yes, you're
。 我认为，是的，你
absolutely right. You are going to
完全正确。 你会
deplete her glucose and you may cause
耗尽她体内的葡萄糖，这可能会引发
some problems and then the muscle will
一些问题，然后肌肉就会
start breaking down. But I do believe
开始分解。 但我相信，
from all the experience that I've had
根据我
with my patients that when I tell them
与患者相处的经验，当我告诉她们
to do HIT, which is high intensity
进行高强度
interal training, all the women do just
间歇训练（HIT）时，所有女性的效果都和
as well as the men because all you're
男性一样好，因为你
doing is you're intensely working the
所做的就是对
muscles and you're doing some resistance
肌肉进行高强度锻炼，进行一些阻力
exercise and then you're totally resting
训练，然后完全休息
as well. And I see fantastic results
。 我看到了非常好的效果
with that.
。
&gt;&gt; In terms of ketosis,
就生酮状态而言，
do you cycle in and out of a ketogenic
你会交替进行生酮饮食和非生酮
diet? And just for anyone that doesn't
饮食吗？ 对于那些还不
know what know, a ketogenic diet is a
了解生酮饮食的人来说，生酮饮食是一种
carbohydrates. So less than 50 grams of
碳水化合物含量非常非常低的饮食。 所以
carbohydrates a day typically. Do you
通常每天摄入的碳水化合物少于50克。 你会时而采用
cycle in and out of that diet?
这种饮食方式，时而又不采用吗？   是的
&gt;&gt; Yes. Yes, you have to because I don't
。 是的，你必须这样做，因为我不想让
want them to stay in a ketogenic state
他们一直处于生酮状态
all the time. So I do I do I do I tell
。 所以我告诉
them, look, look, what is your goal
他们，听着，听着，你们的目标是什么
here? What is your goal? If your goal is
？ 你的目标是什么？ 如果你的目标是
that, okay, I need to lose 70 lbs. Then
，好的，我需要减掉70磅。 然后
you're going to do this till you get to
你就要一直这样做，直到达到
your goal. Once you get to your goal,
你的目标。 一旦达到目标，
then you're going to go back to
你就可以恢复
timerestricted feeding, which means 186.
限时进食，也就是每天摄入186卡路里。
So, you'll still make some ketones. And
所以，你仍然会产生一些酮体。
then intermittently, you can still do a
然后，你仍然可以间歇性地进行
36-hour fast. That means normal, healthy
36 小时禁食。 这意味着像
people, you and me, we should still be
你我这样的正常健康人，仍然应该
doing one 36-hour fast at least once a
至少每月进行一次 36 小时的禁食
month. So, we'll go to that. We'll go to
。 所以，我们就谈到这一点。 我们会去
that. Fasting must still become part of
那里。 禁食仍然应该是
your pro, but you don't need to stay in
你计划的一部分，但你不需要一直保持
ketogenesis all the time. Remember also
生酮状态。 还要记住，
that when you are in ketogenesis you are
当你处于生酮状态时，
you are also in autophagy.
你也处于自噬状态。
How much autophagy can you do? That
你能进行多少自噬？ 这
means you recycling all your your partic
意味着你要回收利用你
all your organels inside your cells.
细胞内的所有颗粒和细胞器。   对于
someone that doesn't know the term
不了解
autophagy?
自噬这个术语的人来说，这简单来说意味着什么？
&gt;&gt; So bottom line is the cell senses that
所以归根结底，细胞感觉到
there is no new parts coming in here. So
没有新的物质进入细胞。 因此，
it takes the redundant
它会将
organels inside the cells and breaks
细胞内多余的细胞器分解
them down, packages them up into these
，将其包装成
little packets and exports them out of
小包，然后将其输出到
the cells. So these cells, all your
细胞外。 所以，你
cells in the body now are functioning at
体内所有的细胞现在都以
a much more efficient level. So
更高的效率运作。 所以
mitochondria
线粒体
also have autophagy. So you're getting
也具有自噬作用。 所以你正在获得
new mitochondria. You're repairing your
新的线粒体。 你正在修复
mitochondria. And you know it's all
线粒体。 你知道这一切都与
about mitochondria, right? Your energy
线粒体有关，对吧？
mitochondria are those organs organels
线粒体是
inside each cell. And we just think of
每个细胞内部的细胞器，是人体的能量来源。 我们只是把
them as only an energy source that oh
它们看作一种能量来源，哦，对了，
yeah my mitochondria they make ATP.
我的线粒体，它们制造ATP。
That's not the whole story. Yes, they
这并非事情的全部真相。 是的，它们会
produce ATP, but they also produce this
产生ATP，但它们也会产生
thing called reactive oxygen species
一种叫做活性氧的物质，
and thereby they influence
从​​而影响
the metabolism of your of your cell as
你细胞的新陈代谢
well. They send signals they send
。 它们会向
signals to your to your chromosomes so
你的染色体发送信号，让
you start producing new proteins. You
你开始产生新的蛋白质。 你
start producing new molecules. So your
开始产生新的分子。 所以你的
mitochondria are very important. If you
线粒体非常重要。 如果你的
have old mitochondria, you're going to
线粒体老化，你就会
have fatigue, tiredness. But when you
感到疲劳乏力。 但是，当你
get mphagy, one reason why you feel so
摄入大量营养物质时，
good after a fast because you have new
禁食后感觉良好的原因之一是，你拥有了新的
mitochondria, they are much more
线粒体，它们
efficient in producing ATP and less
在产生 ATP 方面效率更高，
reactive oxygen species. So you have
活性氧物质也更少。 这样一来，细胞就能进行
mphagy, recycling of your parts,
吞噬作用，回收利用细胞内的物质，
cellular function improves, toxins get
改善细胞功能，
out of your cells as well, toxins.
同时也能排出毒素。
Do you think there's a preferable or a
你认为哪种
best exercise for heart health? Like if
运动对心脏健康更有益？ 比如，如果
you were going to say Stephen to make,
你要说斯蒂芬要做什么，
you know, my my I think my family has a
你知道，我的天，我想我的家族有
history of heart related issues. One of
心脏病史。
my my uncle died from a heart attack. So
我的一位叔叔死于心脏病。 所以
I'm very aware of
我很清楚
my own susceptibility to heart related
自己很容易患上心脏
illnesses. I think there's other people
疾病。 我觉得我家里还有其他人也
in my family um that have heart related
有心脏方面的
issues as well. Is there a particular
问题。 有没有哪种
exercise that is best for the heart? Cuz
运动对心脏特别好？ 因为
I'm guessing resistance training, i.e.
我猜想，阻力训练，也就是
strength training might not be the the
力量训练，可能并不是保持
number one recommendation for good heart
心脏
health. You mentioned HIT. I'm wondering
健康的首选方法。 你提到了HIT。 我想知道答案
if that's
是
Yes. So, I'm just going to tell you
否定的。 所以，我只想
broadly speaking what I see in my
大致说说我在
practice. I see that people who do
实践中看到的情况。 我发现有些人
overly do aerobic activity. That means
过度进行有氧运动。 这意味着
they cycle 100 miles a day or they're
他们每天骑行 100 英里，或者
at a time every day. They're doing a lot
每天在跑步机上跑步两个小时。 他们一直在进行大量的
of lot of marathon training all the
马拉松训练
time. They actually end up with more
。 实际上，与
than patients who do short sprints and
进行短跑冲刺、
patients who do resistance exercises and
阻力训练和
patients who do hits. So in terms of
冲击训练的患者相比，他们体内的炎症反应更严重，患冠状动脉疾病的风险也更高。 所以从
cardiology, you look, you need some
心脏病学的角度来看，你需要进行一些
aerobic training. Why? Because you want
有氧训练。 为什么？ 因为你想
to develop some endurance, right? You
增强耐力，对吧？ 你肯定
don't want to be running behind the bus
不想追着公交车跑，结果跑了
few hundred feet. So for some endurance,
几百米就气喘吁吁。 所以为了增强耐力，
you do aerobic activity. How much
你可以进行有氧运动。 进行多少
aerobic activity which is running on the
有氧运动，
treadmill for example or just sprinting?
例如在跑步机上跑步或短跑？   大约
Only about 15 to 20 minutes. That's it.
只需15到20分钟。 就是这样。
So I tell patients you want to run on
所以我告诉病人，你们要先在
that treadmill, you want to bicycle 15
跑步机上跑步，骑自行车 15
to 20 minutes and then you got to go
到 20 分钟，然后再进行
into resistance exercises. The
阻力训练。
resistance exercises that I have seen
我发现
work best in my patients is simple
对我的病人来说，最有效的阻力训练往往是一些简单的
things. You don't have to go crazy. You
运动。 你没必要大惊小怪。 你
do flow exercises. You use your own body
做流动练习。 你利用自身
weight as resistance. So you can do the
体重作为阻力。 所以你可以做
planks and leg lifts and all these other
平板支撑、抬腿以及其他各种
exercise and you can do hit but they
运动，也可以做高强度间歇训练，但这些运动
have to be very specific. So you
必须非常具体。 所以你要
exercise really hard for about 30
非常努力地锻炼大约 30
seconds to 45 seconds and then you
到 45 秒，然后
completely rest for another 30 to 45
完全休息 30 到 45
seconds.
秒。
&gt;&gt; Okay?
好的？
&gt;&gt; And that's allowing your body to clean
这样可以让你的身体
up the reactive oxygen species you just
清除你在
created through that exercise. Because
运动过程中产生的活性氧。 因为这是
your rate limiting step in cleaning up
清除运动过量产生的代谢废物的限速步骤，所以
get too much exercise, it's a rate
它是一个
limiting step. your glutathione
限速步骤。 你的谷胱甘肽
production, your superoxide dismutase
生成量，你的超氧化物歧化酶
production. These are chemicals that
生成量。 这些化学物质可以
clean up the metabolic mess that you get
清除运动
when you get too much activity. That's a
过量时产生的代谢废物。 这是一个
rate limiting step. So when you rest,
限速步骤。 所以，当你休息、
you exercise and you rest, you exercise,
锻炼、休息、锻炼、
you rest, you are going to get a cleaner
休息时，
&gt;&gt; with your patients. How many patients do
你的病人就会拥有更健康的生理状态。
you think you've treated or worked with
你认为
in your career?
在你职业生涯中，你治疗或接触过多少患者？
&gt;&gt; you have to guess to the nearest
你需要精确到
thousand?
千位吗？
&gt;&gt; It would have to be at least nothing
至少得不少于
less than nothing less than quarter
二十
million.
五万美元。
&gt;&gt; How do you deal with the heartbreak? And
你如何应对失恋的痛苦？ 我
that's no pun intended, but I'm saying
这么说并非有意双关，我的意思是，
like how do you deal with the heartbreak
你该如何面对眼睁睁
of watching people's lives
看着人们
either them losing their life or their
失去生命或
their lives being changed permanently
生活永远改变的痛苦，
forever or dealing with the families of
或者如何面对那些
of people who lose their husband or wife
失去丈夫、妻子、
or or or son or daughter.
儿子或女儿的家庭的悲痛。
It it's very difficult especially when
这非常困难，尤其是在
we've been trying everything and still
我们已经尝试了所有方法之后，
things can go wrong. Based on that, I've
事情仍然可能出错。 基于此，我
realized that sometimes you can do
意识到，有时你可以
everything to try to extend life, but
竭尽全力延长生命，但
you cannot. Life is still finite. We
你却无法做到。 生命终究是有限的。 我们
will pass. Yes, but we want better
会通过。 是的，但我们想要更长的
health span and we want a longer
健康寿命，我们想要更长的
lifespan. I want to give the patients a
寿命。 我也想让患者拥有
better quality of life also. I can't
更好的生活质量。 我无法
make you live forever. I will see people
让你永生。 我会亲眼目睹
die. Sometimes they die in front of me
死亡。 有时，他们就死在我面前，
while I'm even holding their hands.
我甚至还握着他们的手。
They'll pass away in the hospital right
他们会在医院里去世
there. But what I do want to do is to
。 但我希望在此之前，
give them a quality of life until then
能让他们拥有高质量的生活，而这种情况
that's going to change. And in all this
终将改变。 而这一切
education,
教育，
it's all so that you can live an optimal
都是为了让你过上最好的
life and then pass away just like that.
生活，然后就那样悄然离世。
&gt;&gt; Have you seen many people that made all
你见过很多每次都做出
the right decisions? They were healthy.
正确决定的人吗？ 他们都很健康。
They had a good diet. They were doing
他们的饮食很健康。 他们当时正在
exercise and they still end up passing
锻炼，结果却
away on your hospital table because of
因为
heart related illnesses.
心脏疾病死在了医院的手术台上。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yes. Yes.
。 是的。
&gt;&gt; Give me one such example.
请举一个例子。
&gt;&gt; Typical example of fellow in the 60s.
六十年代典型的年轻人的例子。
His coronary calcium score was over
他的冠状动脉钙化评分超过
1,000. So you know that's a CT scan that
1000。 所以你知道，我们做的是CT扫描，
we do and it looks at calcium on the
它可以检查动脉壁上的钙化情况
arteries of the of the wall. So all this
。 所以
plaque that you you you showed this
你看到的这些斑块，这些
yellow stuff here, all that has calcium
黄色的东西，里面都含有钙
in it. So the more calcium you have, the
。 所以，体内钙含量越高，
more plaque you have. So he had a
牙菌斑就越多。 他的
calcium score of over a thousand. So sit
钙化积分超过了一千。 所以，坐下来
down and talk with him and say, "Okay,
和他谈谈，问问他：“好吧，
so tell me why do you have all this
告诉我，你为什么体内有这么多
calcium? No diabetes, no high blood
钙？没有糖尿病，没有
pressure. Doc, I don't even drink. I
高血压。医生，我甚至不喝酒。我
don't do anything. I don't smoke. I
什么运动都不做。我不抽烟。我
exercise regularly. I go to the gym."
经常锻炼。我去健身房。”
And then the question is, why do you
那么问题来了，为什么
have all this coronary calcium in your
你的冠状动脉里会有这么多冠状动脉钙化呢
coronary arteries now? And it turned out
？ 结果发现，
that ever since he was a kid, he had a
他从小就有
bad microbiome.
肠道菌群失衡的问题。
And in him, I found that that was the
而我发现，这就是
reason why he got it. So he was shocked
他得到它的原因。 所以
when he left the office. He was totally
他离开办公室时感到非常震惊。 他非常
shocked because he thought that being
震惊，因为他认为
constipated and having a bowel movement
便秘，
every three or four days
每三四天排便一次
is just normal because it was always
是正常的，因为他一直都是
like that for him until I dug into it
这样，直到我深入调查后
and found out that he's actually got a
发现他实际上有
lot of GI problems and that's what
很多胃肠道问题，这很
probably caused him to have inflammation
可能是导致他发炎的原因，
and that's what's probably caused him to
也可能是导致他
have coronary artery disease. That's why
患上冠状动脉疾病的原因。 这就是
he's got all this coronary
他冠状动脉
calcification.
钙化的原因。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah. So let's talk about the gut
。 那么，我们就来谈谈肠道
microbiome then. You you mentioned
微生物群吧。 您
earlier that that's really pertinent in
之前提到过，这在
cardiovascular issues. Can you explain
心血管疾病方面非常重要。 你能
to me exactly why and how that happens?
详细解释一下为什么会发生这种情况以及具体是如何发生的吗？
The biggest difference between you and
你与外部环境之间最大的区别
your outer environment is actually your
其实在于你的
gut, not outside your skin. It's
肠道，而不是你的皮肤之外的东西。
actually the gut. There's a 100 trillion
其实是肠子。 你的肠道里有 100 万亿个
bacteria sitting in there and there's
细菌，
probably 400 trillion viruses sitting in
可能还有 400 万亿个病毒，
your gut and they're not just hitching a
它们可不是
ride for you. They are there doing
搭便车来到你身边的。 他们在那里做着
something. There's a symbiotic
什么事。
relationship between the gut and you.
肠道与人体之间存在着共生关系。
They produce micronutrients which get
它们产生的微量营养素会
absorbed into your bloodstream. If the
被人体血液吸收。 如果体内
right microbiome is not present, you are
缺乏合适的微生物群，你就
being deprived of those micronutrients.
无法获得这些微量营养素。
For example, short chain fatty acids
例如，短链脂肪酸
which are special kind of uh thing but
是一种特殊的东西，
also they maintain the integrity of the
它们可以维持
lining of the intestines. If the lining
肠道内壁的完整性。 如果
of the intestines is breached then
肠道内壁破损，
bacteria wall products get into the
细菌细胞壁产物就会进入
bloodstream and the first place they'll
血液，它们首先
get to is the liver. Hence you get a
到达的地方就是肝脏。 因此你会患上
fatty liver. There are basically three
脂肪肝。
reasons for fatty liver. Either you're
脂肪肝的成因主要有三种。 要么是你
drinking too much alcohol or you get a
饮酒过量，要么是你
leaky gut or you have too much insulin
肠漏症，要么是你胰岛素过多，
because insulin causes the conversion of
因为胰岛素会导致
glucose into fat. Right? So you get a
葡萄糖转化为脂肪。 正确的？ 所以你会得
fatty liver.
脂肪肝。
&gt;&gt; When you say leaky gut,
你说的是肠漏症，那
&gt;&gt; so that's a leaky gut.
就是肠漏症。
&gt;&gt; Oh, okay. So leaky gut is when the
哦好的。 肠漏症是指肠道
microbiome is dysfunctional.
微生物群功能失调。
&gt;&gt; The microbiome that is dysfunctional
肠道菌群失调会
causes the integrity of your intestinal
导致肠道
lining to be compromised.
内壁完整性受损。
&gt;&gt; Ah okay.
哦，好的。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah. So now molecules that are supposed
。 所以现在，原本应该
to stay in the gut, dead bacterial wall
留在肠道内的分子，也就是死细菌的细胞壁
products, they call lipopolyaccharides,
产物，被称为脂多糖，
they're supposed to stay in the gut, but
它们原本应该留在肠道内，但
now they get into the bloodstream, they
现在它们进入了血液，沿着
go up the portal vein, and up the portal
门静脉向上流动
vein, they'll end up going straight to
，最终会直接到达
the liver. And when they end up in the
肝脏。 当它们最终进入
liver, they cause that fatty liver. Now
肝脏时，就会导致脂肪肝。 现在
you get this big fatty liver, which
你得了严重的脂肪肝，这会
causes a lot of inflammation. a fatty
导致很多炎症。 脂肪
liver. There's an epidemic of this going
肝。
on today. At least 25% of the population
如今这种现象已经非常普遍了。 目前至少有25%的人口
now have a fatty liver.
患有脂肪肝。
&gt;&gt; And what is upstream from that? Is it is
那么，它的上游是什么呢？ 是因为
it alcohol and all these processed foods
酒精、加工食品之类的东西，
and things like that or
还是
&gt;&gt; it's basically processed foods, sugar
基本上是加工食品、糖
and leaky gut and of course toxins.
、肠漏症，当然还有毒素？
Alcohol being the biggest toxin.
酒精是最大的毒素。
&gt;&gt; Okay.
好的。
&gt;&gt; This is the seat of metabolism. So, as a
这是新陈代谢的场所。 所以，作为一名
cardiologist, I became interested in
心脏病专家，我对这个问题产生了兴趣，
this because I found that if you have a
因为我发现，如果你患有
fatty liver, you're going to be more
脂肪肝，你就更
prone to inflammation
容易出现炎症，
and you're going to be more prone to
也更容易患上
coronary artery disease. When we fix the
冠状动脉疾病。 当我们治疗
fatty liver, we change the diet through
脂肪肝时，我们会通过
fatty by by changing your diet and now
改变你的饮食来改变脂肪肝的状况，让
you start eating real food and not
你开始吃真正的食物，而不是
processed foods and products. when we
加工食品和产品。 当我们
increase the fiber intake so that the
增加纤维摄入量，让
good bacteria start coming back into
有益菌重新回到
your gut and when I give you certain
你的肠道，并且我给你服用一些
supplements to restore all your
补充剂来恢复
nutrition in your body then all of a
你身体的所有营养时，
sudden the progression of coronary
冠状动脉钙化的进程就会突然趋于
calcium flattens out. You see let's say
平缓。 假设你
you came to me for a test and I did a
来我这里做检查，我给你做了
coronary calcium score and it's 500 and
冠状动脉钙化评分，结果是 500，
two years from now it's 800. That means,
两年后变成了 800。这意味着，
wait a second, something's not right
等等，这里肯定有什么地方不对劲
here, right? Your coronary calcium
，对吧？ 你的冠状动脉钙化
should not be going up. Now, I can't get
不应该升高。 现在，我无法
rid of the coronary calcium because
消除冠状动脉钙化，因为
that's plaque in the walls of your
那是动脉壁上的斑块
arteries, but it shouldn't keep going up
，但它不应该继续增加，
because one day it's going to be 2,00.
因为有一天它会达到 2,000。
So, how do I follow how well my
那么，我该如何了解我的
treatment for you is? Is I follow the
治疗效果如何呢？ 我是否关注
coronary calcium score.
冠状动脉钙化评分？
&gt;&gt; And again, the coronary calcium score is
再次强调，冠状动脉钙化评分是
a marker of the amount of plaques,
斑块数量的标志，
&gt;&gt; correct? around the heart and in the
对吗？ 心脏周围和
vessels of the blood.
血管内。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah. In the walls.
。 在墙里。
&gt;&gt; In the blood vessels. Okay. So, you want
在血管中。 好的。 所以，你希望
low coronary calcium.
冠状动脉钙化程度低。
&gt;&gt; Like my calcium score is zero. You
我的钙化评分是零。 你的
the walls of the arteries. So, we have
动脉壁上不应该有任何冠状动脉钙化。 现在，我们有了
the yard sticks now.
衡量标准。
&gt;&gt; We should probably we should probably
我们或许应该
differentiate between calcium
区分一下钙
supplements and the calcium that you're
补充剂和你
talking about.
所说的钙。
&gt;&gt; So, pertinent. Calcium supplements
所以，很贴切。 钙补充剂
actually increase the risk of
实际上会增加
cardiovascular events. Calcium
心血管疾病的风险。
supplements should not be taken. The
不应服用钙补充剂。
problem is not calcium supplements. The
问题不在于钙补充剂。
problem is lack of D3 and lack of K2.
问题是缺乏D3和K2。
&gt;&gt; So, we shouldn't be taking calcium
所以，我们不应该服用钙
supplements.
补充剂。
&gt;&gt; Absolutely not.
绝对不是。
&gt;&gt; Absolutely. I stop all calcium
绝对地。 我停止所有
supplements on all my cardiac patients
心脏病患者服用钙补充剂，
and I tell them you should take vitamin
并告诉他们应该服用维生素
D3 so you'll absorb calcium better into
D3，这样可以更好地吸收肠道中的钙；
your gut and you take vitamin K2 because
还要服用维生素K2，因为
vitamin K2 is going to make sure that
维生素K2可以确保
you don't get the calcium build up in
钙不会在
the wrong places in your vascule for
血管的错误部位积聚。例如，为了
&gt;&gt; just to give some context on the
提供一些
research some some large observational
研究背景，一些大型观察性
studies suggest that highdose calcium
研究表明，高剂量钙
supplements which is especially um above
补充剂（尤其是
1,000 milligs a day from pills may
每天超过1000毫克的片剂）可能会
increase the risk of heart attack and
增加心脏病发作和
stroke while others find no clear link.
中风的风险，而其他研究则未发现明确的联系。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
。
&gt;&gt; Okay.
好的。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah. No, I look also they advise high
。 不，我看到他们也建议
calcium supplements in women to prevent
女性补充大量钙质以预防
osteoporosis for example, right? And
骨质疏松症，对吗？ 还有
osteopenia. I live in Florida and all
骨质减少症。 我住在佛罗里达州，
these young women they come to me in
这些年轻女性都
their 30s. They all have osteopenia. And
三十多岁了才来找我。 他们都患有骨质减少症。
the question is that they got calcium
问题是，他们
supplements put inside the milk in the
在牛奶里添加了钙补充剂，
orange juice has calcium in it and
橙汁里也含有钙，而且
they're taking calcium supplements. Then
他们还在服用钙补充剂。 那么，
why would they and they have sunshine
为什么他们生活在阳光充足的地方，
and why would they have osteopenia? And
还会患上骨质减少症呢？
the reason is D3. You need D3 and K2.
原因在于D3。 你需要D3和K2。
That's what you need. It's a hormonal
这就是你需要的。 这是激素方面的
thing. It's not the elemental thing.
问题。 这不是基本要素的问题。
&gt;&gt; So when people are on blood thinners, do
那么，服用血液稀释剂的人
they typically have low vitamin K1?
通常体内维生素K1含量会很低吗？
&gt;&gt; If you're taking couadin, couadin is a
如果你正在服用华法林，华法林是
type of blood thinner. Yeah.
一种血液稀释剂。 是的。
&gt;&gt; That lowers your your vitamin K1 levels
这会降低你体内的维生素K1水平，
and it'll also lower K2. So couadin will
也会降低维生素K2水平。 所以考达因也会
lower K2 as well. So you will get
降低K2值。 因此，
increased coronary calcification and
冠状动脉钙化会增加，
that's been documented. So patients who
这一点已有文献记载。 因此，
have who are taking warrin for example
服用华法林
or couadin have been shown to have
或可丁等药物的患者，
of the fact that the K2 levels come down
由于 K2 水平
as well as the K1 levels both come down
和 K1 水平都会下降，导致冠状动脉钙化增加
both. So you need vitamin K2.
。 所以你需要维生素K2。
&gt;&gt; And you just do you supplement that or
你是通过补充剂还是
do you get it from dietary? I supplement
从饮食中摄取的？ 我给
it on all my patients because diet comes
所有患者都补充维生素K2，因为我们的饮食主要
from fermented foods and we don't eat
来自发酵食品，而我们摄入的
enough fermented foods to contain enough
发酵食品不足以提供足够的
vitamin K2. So one of the reasons why I
维生素K2。 我
do like my supplements is because
喜欢服用营养补充剂的原因之一是，
today's food is not as rich as it was in
现在的食物不如
the past.
过去那么营养丰富了。
So we're not eating the variety of
所以，我们不仅没有摄入足够种类的
foods, but also we're not getting enough
食物，而且
vitamin K2 in our regular diet. So, if
在日常饮食中也没有摄取足够的维生素 K2。 所以，如果
you want to give me advice then on
你想给我一些建议，那就告诉我如何
having a great gut so that I don't end
拥有健康的肠道，这样我就不会患上
up with leaky gut which will cause all
肠漏症，从而引发所有
of these downstream effects. What is um
这些后续影响。 请问，要想
what is the advice you'd give me to have
拥有完美的肠道健康，您有什么建议
a perfect gut? Number one, lots of fiber
？ 第一，要摄入大量纤维，
because the fiber is going to be eaten
因为纤维会被
by your bacteria and you're going to get
细菌吃掉，这样就能培养出
a wide variety of good bacteria eating
各种各样的有益细菌来分解
fiber. If you eat a lot of sugar, you'll
纤维。 如果你吃很多糖，也会
get bacteria too, but there are the bad
滋生细菌，但其中有些是有害的
ones, the ones that you don't want. So
细菌，是你不希望看到的。
SIBO, for example. But you want to eat
例如，你可能会患上一种叫做小肠细菌过度生长（SIBO）的疾病。 但你要摄入
lots of fiber. So because our diets
大量膳食纤维。 由于我们
today don't give us enough fiber, I do
今天的饮食无法提供足够的纤维，所以我
advise all my patients to take inulin
建议我的所有患者服用菊粉
with FOS. It's called inulin with FOS.
和低聚果糖。 它被称为含低聚果糖的菊粉。
It's a powder. It's a soluble fiber. And
它是一种粉末。 它是一种可溶性纤维。
I just tell them to take one scoop in
我就告诉他们每天在水里加一勺，
your water every day or put it in your
或者加到
whatever you're going to have, whatever
你要喝的任何
liquid you're going to have. Number two,
液体里。 第二，
fermented foods.
发酵食品。
The fermented foods will give you not
发酵食品不仅能提供
only the bacteria themselves because,
细菌本身（
for example, kefir has so many different
例如，开菲尔含有许多不同的
strains of good bacteria, but they also
有益细菌菌株），而且还
have the postbiotics. What is a
含有后生元。 什么是
postbiotic? A postbiotic, for example,
后生元？ 例如，后生元，
vitamin K2. It's a product that the
维生素 K2。 这是
bacteria make.
细菌产生的一种产物。
Short chain fatty acids. That's a
短链脂肪酸。 那是
product that the bacteria make. So, you
细菌产生的一种产物。 所以，你
want bacteria. You want good bacteria in
想要细菌。 你需要肠道内有益菌，
your gut and they will stabilize the
它们能稳定肠道
ratio of all the other bacteria in your
内其他细菌的比例
gut. So the keystone species have to
。 所以关键物种必须重新
come back into your gut.
回到你的肠道中。
&gt;&gt; I was reading some research around fiber
我读了一些关于膳食纤维的研究，研究
and it says that in the United States
显示，在美国，
women are 40% fiber deficient and men
女性膳食纤维摄入不足的比例为 40%，男性膳食
are roughly 50% fiber deficient. And in
纤维摄入不足的比例约为 50%。
the UK we're about 40% fiber deficient.
英国约有40%的人膳食纤维摄入不足。
I don't think people know that. Where do
我觉得人们并不了解这一点。 哪里可以
I find fiber? What what do I need to be
找到纤维？ 我应该
eating to increase my fiber?
吃些什么来增加膳食纤维的摄入量？
nonprocessed
未经加工的食物中都含有纤维，
because the very act of a processed food
因为加工食品的目的
is to take out the fiber so that you can
就是去除纤维，从而
increase the shelf life of it. So any
延长其保质期。 所以任何
processed food, anything that's
加工食品，
manufactured in a factory for example,
例如工厂生产的食品，
anything that already comes ready made,
任何现成的食品，
they've taken the fiber right out of it.
都去除了其中的纤维。
So you got to eat real food. So you're
所以你得吃真正的食物。 所以你
going to eat real vegetables and that to
要吃真正的蔬菜，而且是
a variety of vegetables. You see, you're
各种各样的蔬菜。 你看，你
supposed to eat 30 to 40 different types
应该每周吃 30 到 40 种不同的
of vegetables a week and we don't tend
蔬菜，但我们往往
to do that. So you want fiber from a
做不到这一点。 所以你需要来自
variety of sources. So we got to eat a
多种来源的纤维。 所以我们有机会品尝到各种
different kind of vegetables including
不同的蔬菜，包括
spices. They all count as one vegetable.
香料。 它们都算作一种蔬菜。
So that's something I I stress to
所以我一直向
everybody that you got to have variety.
大家强调，一定要多样化。
You got to have all these different
你必须摄入各种不同的
fibers because they will foster the
纤维，因为它们会促进
species in your gut.
肠道内不同类型细菌的生长。
&gt;&gt; What about lifestyle? recommendations
生活方式方面呢？
for improving my gut things like I don't
关于改善肠道健康的建议，比如
know stress sleep exercise anything
压力、睡眠、运动等等，我不太清楚。
&gt;&gt; sleep absolutely important so the the
睡眠绝对重要，所以
the next thing is actually actually
接下来要说的其实是
sleep and stress because lack of sleep
睡眠和压力，因为睡眠不足会
causes a change in your gut microbiome
导致肠道菌群发生变化。
you got to sleep 7 hours a night and
你每晚需要睡7个小时，
cutting down on sleep is going to affect
减少睡眠会影响
your entire physiology in your body and
你身体的整个生理机能、
your repair processes and your vagus
修复过程、迷走
nerve and your delta sleep
神经和δ睡眠，还会影响
But also your gut microbiome. One night
你的肠道菌群。 一夜之间，
you'll get insulin resistance. One night
你就会患上胰岛素抵抗。 一晚
of bad sleep, you become insulin
睡眠不足，第二天就会出现胰岛素
resistant the next day.
抵抗。
If you're changing
如果
if you're changing time zones very
你经常变换时区
frequently,
，
the liver dysfunctions
肝脏功能
and the gut microbiome also
和肠道微生物群也会出现
dysfunctions.
功能紊乱。
So we got to be more cognizant of that.
所以我们必须更加重视这一点。
That lifestyle is very important.
这种生活方式非常重要。
And we have to have plenty omega3 in the
而且我们的饮食中必须摄入足够的omega-3脂肪酸
diet.
。
&gt;&gt; If you're starting a business, that
如果你要创业，那就
means you're one person doing the
意味着你一个人要承担
workload of probably about 50 people.
大约 50 个人的工作量。
When I first founded this podcast, I had
当我最初创办这个播客时，我完全
no idea that I was about to step into a
没有想到自己即将承担
hundred different roles that I'd never
一百种我从未接受过培训的不同角色
trained for. Things like researching and
。 比如调研、
production and scheduling and branding,
制作、排期和品牌推广等等，
all of it all at once. And this
所有这些都要同时进行。 而且这种
experience isn't unique to me. But for
经历并非我独有。 但对于
millions of founders around the world,
全球数百万创业者来说，
the tool that changes all of that is our
改变这一切的工具正是我们的
sponsor, Shopify. Shopify now powers 10%
赞助商 Shopify。  Shopify 目前为美国 10% 的电子商务提供技术支持
of all US e-commerce. From names like
。 从
Gym Shark and Mattel to first-time
Gym Shark 和 Mattel 这样的知名企业到刚刚
founders just getting started. It's like
起步的创业新手。 它就像
having your very own design studio,
将您自己的设计工作室、
content creator, and marketing team in
内容创作团队和营销团队
one with hundreds of online store
合二为一，拥有数百个在线商店
templates, AI tools to create product
模板、用于创建产品页面的 AI 工具
pages, and easy to launch email and
以及易于启动的电子邮件和
social media plugins. Behind the scenes,
社交媒体插件。  Shopify 在后台
Shopify manages your inventory,
管理您的库存、
international shipping, and even your
国际运输，甚至
returns. So, if you're ready to sell,
退货。 所以，如果您准备好销售，请
sign up for your $1 a month trial at
访问 shopify.com/bartlet 注册，即可享受每月 1 美元的试用价
shopify.com/bartlet.
。
That's shopify.com/bartlet.
那是 shopify.com/bartlet。
$1 a month. No way.
每月1美元。 决不。
You talk you talked earlier on about
你之前谈到过
toxins.
毒素。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
。
&gt;&gt; What do you mean by toxins and how what
你说的毒素是什么意思？
role is toxins playing in my physiology
毒素在我的生理机能
and my heart health and my gut health?
、心脏健康和肠道健康中扮演着什么角色？   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah. So,
。 那么，
&gt;&gt; and what is a toxin?
什么是毒素？
&gt;&gt; A toxin is a molecule
毒素是指
that should not be in your body. You
不应该存在于你体内的分子。 你本
should not have been exposed to it. So,
不应该接触到它。 假设我们
let's take a pesticide or a herbicide.
以杀虫剂或除草剂为例。
These are chemicals
这些是
which man has made and not perhaps
人类制造的化学物质，但可能还没有经过
adequately tested it in in um in
充分的
rigorous studies. And yet these
严格研究测试。 然而，这些
chemicals get into the body and we know
化学物质会进入人体，我们知道其中
that many of them are estrogen receptor
许多是雌激素受体
disruptors and that causes inflammation
干扰物，这也会导致炎症
as well. So if you look at pesticides
。 所以，如果你看看杀虫剂
and herbicides,
和除草剂，
we look at plastics
我们就会发现塑料中的
forever chemicals for example PAS and
化学物质，例如 PAS 和
other chemical BPA.
其他化学物质 BPA。
These chemicals all disrupt our
这些化学物质都会扰乱
metabolism in our body. And then of
我们体内的新陈代谢。 当然，
course mold is a toxin. And lastly,
霉菌也是一种毒素。 最后，
heavy metals are toxins.
重金属是毒素。
When the gut is not working properly,
当肠道功能失调时，
you're going to be more prone to
你会更容易
toxicity because the gut bacteria
中毒，因为肠道细菌
normally grab a lot of those things and
通常会吸收很多毒素并通过
take them out in your stools. So when we
粪便排出体外。 所以，当我们
look at toxicity, we look at gut health
关注毒性时，我们会关注肠道健康
and the liver health. The liver is
和肝脏健康。 肝脏
supposed to get rid of lot of toxins.
应该能够清除很多毒素。
But in today's day and age, because of
但是，在当今时代，由于
the foods that we're eating, the
我们所吃的食物、
environment that we breathe, the
我们呼吸的环境、
environment that we walk out into, we
我们所处的环境，我们
getting too many toxins and this poor
摄入了太多的毒素，这个可怜的
organ here is getting overwhelmed and
器官不堪重负，
cannot detoxify adequately. So when I do
无法充分解毒。 所以，当我进行
a blood test, urine sample, and a stool
血液检查、尿液样本和粪便
sample, I get a very good bird's eye
样本检查时，我就可以非常清楚地
view of what's going on with their
了解他们的
ability to detoxify and which levels are
解毒能力以及哪些指标
high. And I'm finding
偏高。 我发现，
that many of my patients who have gut
我的许多肠胃
issues and liver issues are very, very
和肝脏有问题的病人，
high with not only heavy metals, but
不仅体内重金属含量非常高，而且
herbicides, and mold in their body.
体内还有大量的杀虫剂、除草剂和霉菌。
and mold. I'm finding a lot of mold and
以及霉菌。 我发现了很多霉菌，
mold and all these extraneous toxicities
而且这些外来毒素都会
cause inflammation. Inflammation is a
引起炎症。 炎症是
reaction to something that your body
身体对
shouldn't have.
不应该存在的物质的一种反应。
&gt;&gt; Where is the mold coming from?
霉菌是从哪里来的？
&gt;&gt; Mold is very interesting. I've only
霉菌非常有趣。 我才
started researching it in the last one
开始研究这个课题
year.
一年左右。
Basically,
基本上，
almost 70% of homes these days have some
如今近 70% 的房屋都存在某种
form of mold toxicity in them, either
形式的霉菌毒性，要么是
from previous water damage or exposure.
由于以前的水灾造成的，要么是由于接触造成的。
And mold is ubiquitous. It's it's just
霉菌无处不在。 它几乎无处不在
about everywhere. And it can
。 而且
reininoculate you every time you're in
每次你​​身处那种环境，它都会让你再次感染
that environment. and it causes your
。 它会引发你体内
innate immune system to start reacting
固有的免疫系统
to it and causes lowgrade inflammation
对其产生反应，从而导致体内出现低度炎症
in your body. And when I get rid of the
。 当我清除
mold, all of a sudden I'm noticing that
霉菌后，我突然发现
the patients are not only feeling
患者不仅感觉
better, but the rate of progression of
好多了，而且冠状动脉疾病的进展速度也趋于
coronary artery disease flattens off. I
平缓。
have this uh steam room in one of my
我的房子里有个蒸汽房，
houses and uh I went in there the other
前几天我进去的时候闻到
bit funny and I recognized that smell
一股怪味，我小时候就闻到过这种味道，那是霉味
from when I was younger as being mold.
。
So I like I googled it what what is that
于是我就上网查了一下，想看看
like earthy strong pungent smell in my
我蒸汽房里那股像泥土一样浓烈刺鼻的气味是什么
steam room. I think what's happened is
。 我觉得可能是
part of the like seat has come away from
座椅的一部分从
the wall so it's not sealed anymore and
墙上脱落了，所以不再密封了，
I think the moisture has got in there
水汽渗进去了，可能发霉了。
and chachi said to me when I was asking
我问过
chap said smell near the like cracks
Chachi，他说闻闻缝隙附近，如果缝隙附近味道很浓，那就是发霉了。
and I smelled near the crack and it was
我闻了闻缝隙附近，味道真的非常浓，当时我就想，
oh like so I had I not known that would
哦，原来如此。如果我不知道的话，我
day inhaling all of that strong mold
每天要在那里坐30分钟，吸入那么多浓烈的
smell. And from doing this show, I've
霉味。 通过参加这个节目，我
I've learned that the downstream impacts
了解到它对
that can have on your body and your
你的身体、
cardiovascular health and everything in
心血管健康以及其他各方面造成的后续影响真的
between is really, really bad. So, I I
非常糟糕。 所以我叫了
had a team come over and just uh fix
一个团队过来，把
everything, repair it, and do a deep
所有东西都修好、修理好，并进行了一次彻底的
clean. But I don't think people are very
清洁。 但我认为人们并没有
aware of how mold, which we kind of
意识到霉菌（我们通常
think of as like, oh, the the the bread
认为霉菌就是面包
has gone green,
变绿了之类的）
&gt;&gt; whatever, can have a chronic downstream
会造成长期的后续
&gt;&gt; impact. And also this mold can come in
影响。 而且这种霉菌还会侵入你
and then become part of your microbiome.
的体内，成为你肠道菌群的一部分。
So it can actually come into your so
所以它实际上可以进入你的生活，比如说，
let's say you get out of this place. But
你离开这个地方。 但是，
if the mold is still in your gut or if
如果霉菌仍然留在你的肠道中，或者
it's in your sinuses for example and you
例如，如果它在你的鼻窦中，并且你
get chronic sinusitis you're
患上了慢性鼻窦炎，那么你就不断地将
again with this mold. And this is an
这种霉菌重新接种到自己体内。 这是一个
area of great interest and a lot of
非常值得关注的领域，
research needs to be done. It is real
需要进行大量的研究。 这是真的，
and we've known about it for a long
而且我们早就知道了
time. But the medical profession as a
。 但医学界
general has not really taken this and
总体上并没有真正重视这一点
run with it, but it is very important
，但这非常重要，
and we certainly looking at mold
我们当然会
toxicity in our practice because we find
在实践中关注霉菌毒性，因为我们发现
that it is actually more prevalent than
它实际上比
we ever ever imagined before and we know
我们以前想象的要普遍得多，而且我们也了解它的
the chemistry. We know that it causes a
化学性质。 我们知道它会引起
body and it's reflected in the blood
身体的全身性炎症反应，这在血液检查中也有所体现
work. We see that the CRP is up. We see
。 我们看到CRP上升了。 我们看到
that the compliment levels are high. we
赞扬声很高。 我们
see that the certain ratios of certain
发现某些
inflammatory molecules are off. So we do
炎症分子的比例失调了。 所以我们确实
want to treat mold. Um we want to treat
需要处理霉菌。 我们希望治疗
sources of mold toxicity both in the gut
肠道和鼻窦中的霉菌毒性源
as well as in the sinuses. And yes,
。 是的，
people are surprised when I tell that
当我说
that affects the cardiovascular health.
这会影响心血管健康时，人们都很惊讶。
&gt;&gt; When we talk about the clogging of
当我们谈到
arteries, why is it that healthy people
动脉阻塞时，为什么健康的人
still end up sometimes with these
有时也会出现
clogged arteries? I think it's because
动脉阻塞呢？ 我认为这是因为
they have sources of inflammation that
他们体内存在
we have not identified. For example, we
我们尚未发现的炎症源。 例如，我们会
say, "Oh, you have no cholesterol, you
说：“哦，你没有胆固醇，你
have no smoking, you have you're
不吸烟，你在
exercising, you're not overweight, you
锻炼，你不超重，你也
don't have diabetes." Well, then I don't
没有糖尿病。” 那我就不
know why you got all these odd. No,
知道你为什么会收到这么多奇怪的东西了。 不，
there's always if you dig deeper inside,
只要你深入挖掘，
there's always something. And we'll find
总会有东西的。 我们会找到
the source of the inflammation. There's
炎症的根源。
the arteries.
动脉硬化总是有原因的。
&gt;&gt; What's in that list?
清单上有什么？
&gt;&gt; In that list is mold.
名单里有霉菌。
&gt;&gt; Mold. Yeah.
模具。 是的。   舔舔
&gt;&gt; Licky gut. Yeah,
肚子。 是的，对
&gt;&gt; huge food sensitivities. Oh, let me tell
食物严重过敏。 哦，让我来跟
you about food sensitivities. So,
你说说食物过敏吧。 所以，
another reason for the leaky gut is that
肠漏症的另一个原因是
certain foods punch holes into your
某些食物会在你的肠道上打孔，
intestines in a in a in a sense and
从某种意义上说，从而
causes a leaky gut. And I've had at
导致肠漏症。
least one patient in the last 6 weeks
在过去的 6 周里，我至少遇到过一位患有
celiac disease and he didn't even
乳糜泻的病人，他自己都没有
realize he had celiac disease because he
意识到患有乳糜泻，因为他
had no constipation, diarrhea and he had
没有便秘或腹泻，而且他还患有
premature coronary artery disease and we
早发性冠状动脉疾病，我们后来才
identified that he had celiac disease.
发现他患有乳糜泻。
We cut out all weight from his diet and
我们让他从饮食中完全减重，
that's going to stop this inflammatory
这样就能阻止炎症的发生
process from occurring. See, it's all
。 你看，这一切都与
about inflammation. We need to get rid
炎症有关。 我们需要消除
of inflammation in order to get rid of
炎症才能消除
coronary artery disease. Any source of
冠状动脉疾病。 任何
inflammation,
炎症源，
get rid of the source. So if the
都要消除它。 所以如果
pesticide levels are high, herbicide
农药含量高，或者除草剂
levels are really high, get off that
含量非常高，那就远离那个
source. Maybe you maybe you're living on
来源。 也许你住在
a golf course and you smell those
高尔夫球场附近，每天都能闻到那些
chemicals every day. Maybe you're using
化学物质的味道。 也许你
it yourself in your yard. Maybe you have
自己就在自家院子里用它。
toxicity coming from mold as you
正如你所说，也许你体内的毒素来源于霉菌
mentioned. But we got to find the source
。 但我们必须找到它的源头
of it. So, a thorough evaluation of the
。 因此，需要对
gut microbiome, a thorough evaluation
肠道微生物群进行全面评估，对
of toxins in your body, and a
体内毒素进行全面评估，并评估
nutritional status.
营养状况。
this type of pathology if you have good
如果营养充足，你的身体就能自行清除这类病症
nutrition. We don't have good nutrition
。 我们现在的营养状况不好
today.
。   那我们就来
&gt;&gt; Let's talk about nutrition then. If I
谈谈营养吧。 如果我
wanted to end up on your surgical table,
想要躺在你的手术台上，
if I if that was my goal, what would you
如果那是我的目标，你会
recommend
建议
that I ate and yeah consumed?
我吃些什么，摄入些什么？
&gt;&gt; You should eat nutrient
你每天都应该吃营养
deficient
匮乏的
processed foods every day.
加工食品。
&gt;&gt; Give me some examples of of things.
请举一些例子。
Pringles and
品客薯片，而且
&gt;&gt; correct. So it'll be things made out of
正确。 所以会有
wheat, refined wheat, biscuits, cookies,
小麦制品，精制小麦制品，饼干，曲奇，
cakes, lots of bread. Basically,
蛋糕，还有很多面包。 基本上，
fast foods,
快餐、
foods that come in a box, readymade
盒装食品、
food with labels,
带标签的现成食品、
anything that comes in a packet that you
任何
open up,
包装好的食品，
including some of these
包括一些
that are high protein bars or some of
高蛋白棒之类的东西，
these because they have all sorts of
因为它们含有各种各样的
other chemicals in them.
化学物质。
And I would have lots and lots of um
而且我吃的
those processed foods. Um artificial
那些加工食品里都含有大量的人工色素。 嗯，人工
sweeteners,
甜味剂，还有
lots and lots of diet drinks and sugary
很多很多无糖饮料和含糖
drinks.
饮料。
&gt;&gt; Orange juice.
橙汁。
&gt;&gt; Orange juice is is certainly on my list
橙汁肯定在我的清单上，
because that produces such a profound
因为它会大幅
increase in my glucose level and then my
提高我的血糖水平，然后
afterwards will cause me to become very
随之而来的胰岛素飙升会让我在
hungry 3 to four hours later. So yeah, I
3 到 4 个小时后感到非常饥饿。 所以，没错，我
would not eat real food
不会吃真正的食物，
and you'll end up on my table.
而你最终会成为我餐桌上的盘中餐。
&gt;&gt; See, alcohol, smoking,
你看，喝酒、抽烟，
&gt;&gt; alcohol, no fiber because none of those
喝酒，没有纤维，因为这些
foods will have fiber in them. None of
食物都不含纤维。
those processed foods have fiber in
这些加工食品都不含膳食纤维
them.
。
&gt;&gt; Your patients must come to you at times
您的患者必须时不时地来找您，
and tell you what they're doing in terms
告诉您他们在
of what they're eating and lifestyle
饮食和生活方式
choices. And there must be certain
选择方面的情况。 而且，肯定有一些
things which very people aren't aware
东西对健康不利，只是很多人没有意识到而已
aren't healthy. You actually mentioned
。 你居然提到了
bread.
面包。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
。
&gt;&gt; Is all bread bad?
所有的面包都是不好的吗？
&gt;&gt; No, not all bread is bad. Most bread is
不，并非所有面包都是坏的。 大部分面包都不
bad. I don't mind some sourdough because
好。 我不介意吃点酸面包，因为
it's fermented. So, it's going to get
它发酵过。 这样可以
rid of some of those lectins that are
去除面粉中原有的一些凝集素
already in the flour. So, those lectins
。 所以，这些凝集素
are gone out because they've been
因为
fermented. So, it's probably a little
发酵而消失了。 所以，可能
bit okay. But again, not large amounts
还算可以吧。 但同样，数量并不多
of it. You know, a slice once or twice a
。 你知道，一周吃一两次
week is fine, but really it's a survival
是可以的，但它实际上是一种生存
food. Bread is a survival food. Just
食品。 面包是生存必需品。 只是
empty calories. That's all it's going to
空有热量而已。 它只能
do.
做到这些。
&gt;&gt; Is there like a worse bread? Is there
还有比这更难吃的面包吗？ 有没有
like one bread which is
一种面包叫“是”？
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Pure white bread. Simple white
纯白面包。 简单的白
bread. The simple light white bread.
面包。 简单的白面包。
It's pure calories, 70 calories right
这全是卡路里，足足70卡路里
there. You're talking about just eat
。 你这是在说，
have 10 teaspoons of sugar instead in
在一片面包里放10茶匙糖就好
one slice. I mean, it just doesn't make
。 我的意思是，这完全说不通
any sense whatsoever.
。
&gt;&gt; White rice.
白米饭。
&gt;&gt; White rice. I white rice is a staple
白米饭。 白米饭是
food of many people and they cannot live
许多人的主食，他们离不开
without it. So I run into this problem
它。 所以我经常遇到这个问题
all the time. So I tell them that this
。 所以我告诉他们，
is what you're going to do. You're going
你们要这样做。
to first and foremost soak your rice in
首先，你要把米浸泡在
water and then discard the water after
水中，浸泡一夜后把水倒掉，
an overnight soak because it contains
因为
arsenic in it and other heavy metals.
水里含有砷和其他重金属。
You'll be surprised how much arsenic
你会惊讶于
there's in rice these days. You see see
如今大米中砷的含量之高。 你看，这就是我们
foods. I mean here as a cardiologist has
食品采购方面的问题所在。 我的意思是，在这里，心脏病专家不得不和
to talk to his patients about how to
病人谈论如何
cook rice.
煮米饭。
&gt;&gt; What is arsenic for people that don't
对于不了解的人来说，砷是什么
know?
？
&gt;&gt; It's a heavy metal that is found in the
这是一种存在于
soil and the water is in contaminated
土壤和水中的重金属，这些受污染的
soil and water and in these patty fields
土壤和水体中都含有砷，这些田地
are now full of arsenic.
现在到处都是砷。
&gt;&gt; It's a poison, isn't it? People I watch
那是一种毒药，对吧？ 我喜欢看
a lot of true crime. People kill each
很多真实犯罪题材的节目。 人们
other with arsenic.
用砒霜互相残杀。
&gt;&gt; It's a very very strong poison and it'll
这是一种剧毒物质，会
slowly kill you. Is there anything else
慢慢杀死你。 还有其他关于
on that list of thing misconceptions?
事物误解的清单吗？
&gt;&gt; So, so the rice has to be soaked. Then
所以，米需要浸泡。 然后把
you get rid of the water. Then you cook
水倒掉。 然后
it with lots of water. Throw away the
加大量水煮。 把
rice again. I mean the throw away the
米饭再扔掉。 我的意思是倒掉
water, not the rice. And then you cool
水，而不是米。 然后把
the rice in the refrigerator
米饭放在冰箱里冷却，
and then you eat the rice the next day
第二天再
by reheating it. Now what you've done is
加热食用。 现在
you've created resistance starch.
你已经制备出了抗性淀粉。
Now, what's going to happen is that that
现在，这种
rice is not going to have the same
米饭不会像以前那样
insulin effect in your body and weight
刺激你的胰岛素分泌，也不会像以前那样导致体重增加
gain effect and changes in your
和
metabolism because it's now got
新陈代谢改变，因为它现在含有
resistant starch. Resistant starch means
抗性淀粉。 抗性淀粉是指
that those molecules have all bound to
这些分子彼此之间完全结合
each other. They don't they resist
。 它们不会，它们会抵抗
absorption and digestion until they get
吸收和消化，直到
to your colon. And then who's going to
到达结肠。 那谁来
eat it? Your bacteria. So, you're
吃呢？ 你的细菌。 所以，你
basically feeding the bacteria with your
实际上是在用米饭喂养细菌
rice. So, if you're going to have rice,
。 所以，如果你要吃米饭，就应该这样
this is the way you're going to do it.
做。
So,
那么，除了以上
&gt;&gt; is there anything else on that list that
列出的项目之外，还有什么其他
people should be thinking about that
人们现在
they probably consider to be healthy
可能认为有益健康的事情值得考虑吗
right now?
？   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. So,
。 是的。 是的。 是的。 是的。 是的。 所以，
it's also what you do to your food.
这也跟你如何处理食物有关。   举个
example, and if you burn it and you
例子，你拿一块上好的鱼，如果你把它烧焦了，
blacken it really bad, you're creating
烤得非常黑，你就产生了
what is known as advanced glycation end
所谓的晚期糖基化终
products. You fry something, you're
产物。 你煎炸食物，就会
creating advanced glycation end
产生晚期糖基化终
products. So, let me define that for
产物。 那么，让我来为你解释一下
you. If nature does not have the ability
。 如果大自然本身没有能力
on its own to take
将
glucose, protein and fat and combine
葡萄糖、蛋白质和脂肪
them at very high temperature,
在极高的温度下结合起来，
but you can do it in your air fryer
但你可以在空气炸锅中做到这一点，也
and you can do it outside when you when
可以在户外将
you're blackening your food and over
食物烤焦甚至
blackening your food. It's called
烤过头时做到这一点。 它被称为
advanced glycation end products. So when
晚期糖基化终产物。 所以，当
you over burn your food, when you
你把食物烧焦、煮
overcook your food, you're creating
过头的时候，就会产生
these molecules. Now you're consuming
这些分子。 现在你摄入了
these molecules and they have been shown
这些分子，研究表明，它们会
to cause a radical increase in the
导致
inflammation in your body because your
你体内的炎症急剧增加，因为你的
body reacts to those products. There's
身体会对这些产品产生反应。 人体内存
receptors to get rid of those they
在能清除这些被
called rages and they get rid of these
称为“愤怒”的物质的受体，它们可以清除这些
products but you overwhelm them and now
产物，但如果你使它们不堪重负，就会引发
you get inflammation.
炎症。
&gt;&gt; And is there any other watch out foods
还有哪些食物，
that you know people think are healthy
人们认为它们健康，
but maybe if if I was trying to have an
但如果我想拥有
optimally healthy heart I should avoid
最佳的心脏健康状态，就应该避免食用，需要注意吗？
&gt;&gt; Is this going to surprise you? excessive
这会让你感到惊讶吗？
because I'm not a very big follower of
因为我不太喜欢吃水果，所以买了太多水果
fruit. Fruit should be eaten only in
。 水果应该只在
season because it has too much fructose
当季食用，因为水果中含有过多的果糖
in it.
。
&gt;&gt; Fructose being the sugars.
果糖是糖类。
&gt;&gt; Fructose is sugar and fructose causes
果糖是糖，而果糖会导致
fatty liver. So our overconumption of
脂肪肝。 因此，我们过量食用
fruit is another factor that is
水果是
contributing to coronary artery disease
导致冠状动脉疾病
and diabetes and fatty liver. And we
、糖尿病和脂肪肝的另一个因素。 我们
think of fruit as being a healthy thing.
认为水果是健康食品。
You see, but fruit should only be
你看，水果其实应该只
consumed really in the fall and in
在秋季应季食用，
season and in small amounts because that
而且要少量食用，因为水果中
high fructose level really causes major
高含量的果糖确实会对
changes in your metabolism. So, I'm not
你的新陈代谢造成重大影响。 所以，我对
too front of fruit. You can eat fruit in
水果不太了解。 你可以吃当季水果
season, small amounts of it, but you
，少量即可，但你
know, people go crazy about fruit. I
知道，人们对水果非常着迷。 我的
mean, I had a patient who was having
意思是，我曾有一个病人，他既有
mental problems as well as
精神问题，又有
cardiovascular disease. And he that's
心血管疾病。 他每天
all he lived on is fruit morning, lunch,
早、午、
and dinner. And the moment we stopped
晚都只吃水果。 我们刚一停下来，
that his health changed completely. He
他的健康状况就彻底改变了。 他好多了
got so much better.
。
So excess of fruit is also no good.
所以，水果吃多了也不好。
Excessively cooked foods, processed
过度烹饪的食物、加工
foods, refined products. And another
食品、精制食品。 还有
one, vegetable seed oils. So any food
一种是植物籽油。 所以，任何
that you prepare or you buy that
你烹饪或购买的
contains vegetable seed oils is a no no
含有植物籽油的食物都是不行的，
because vegetable seed oils are a
因为植物籽油是一种
product. And if you look at all of them,
产品。 如果你仔细观察它们，你会发现
they're exceedingly high in omega6. And
它们的omega-6含量都非常高。 而
the problem we have today.
我们今天面临的问题就是ω-6与ω-3的比例失衡。
We have far too much omega6, very little
我们体内omega-6过多，
omega3. So anything that contains
omega-3过少。 所以任何含有
vegetable seed oils. So I always tell my
植物籽油的产品。 所以我总是告诉我的
patients, get rid of that vegetable seed
病人，把家里的那瓶植物籽油扔掉
oil bottle from your home.
。
&gt;&gt; So what oil should I use instead? The
那我应该用哪种油代替呢？
oil at home, if you're going to use any
在家如果要
oil, is going to be olive oil, extra
用油的话，那就用橄榄油，特级
virgin olive oil for your for your
初榨橄榄油拌
salad. And if you're going to do high
沙拉。 如果要用高温烹饪
temperature, put a little pat of butter
，可以放一小块黄油，
or use a little bit of ghee or you can
或者用一点酥油，也可以
use a little bit of coconut oil. This is
用一点椰子油。 这是
a bit more of a different question, but
一个略有不同的问题，但
you said earlier on that when a patient
您之前说过，当病人
walks into your office, you can kind of
走进您的办公室时，您可以
look at them and generally see if their
观察他们，大致了解他们的
cardiovascular health is intact. And
心血管健康状况是否良好。
we're generalizing here, but if I'm sat
我们这里是在概括地描述，但如果我
at home right now and I'm trying to
现在坐在家里，想
figure out if I'm healthy as it relates
弄清楚
to my cardiovascular health, what are
我的心血管健康状况如何，那么
the symptoms of cardiovascular poor
心血管健康状况不佳的症状有哪些呢
health? Like what throughout the whole
？ 比如遍布全身的什么部位
body? What what should I can I sort of
？ 我应该怎么做？我当然
obviously don't want anyone to self
不希望任何人
diagnose at home, but what kind of
在家自行诊断，但是当我看着你的时候，
symptoms should I be looking at when I
我应该注意哪些症状
you when you look at me? Let's do this
？
on me to make it easier.
为了方便起见，我们让我来做吧。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah. So number one, look at your
。 首先，看看你的
weight.
体重。
&gt;&gt; Okay. If you're overweight, that's a
好的。 如果你超重，那已经
that's a that's one strike against you
对你不利了
already. Number two, if you're
。 第二，如果你
overweight, where is it? It's mostly on
超重，那它在哪里？ 主要集中在
the belly.
腹部。
&gt;&gt; I'm overweight according to the BMI.
根据BMI指数，我超重了。
&gt;&gt; But again, you got to look at BMI, you
但是，你也要看看BMI，你
know, is a little crude. It's not a very
知道，它有点粗略。 这种
accurate way of actually looking at it
看待问题的方式并不十分准确，
because some people are very muscular
因为有些人肌肉非常发达，
okay for them. It's the constitution I
他们的 BMI 为 28 实际上完全正常。 我
look at and it's visceral fat. Now, I
关注的是体质，以及内脏脂肪。 现在，我
can't measure your visceral fat by
无法通过观察你的外表来测量你的内脏脂肪
looking at you, but I can tell if your
，但我可以判断你的
belly is protruded. Now, in my office, I
肚子是否凸出。 现在，在我的办公室里，我
do visceral fat analysis.
进行内脏脂肪分析。   还有什么呢
&gt;&gt; So, what else? I've I've I don't have a
？ 我没有明显的
protruding belly per se. Um, what else
凸出肚子。 嗯，为了
should I be looking for to understand if
了解
my cardiovascular health is intact? Is
我的心血管健康状况是否良好，我还应该注意哪些方面呢？
there I know
我光
&gt;&gt; just by looking at you physically.
看外表就能知道你在哪里。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
。
&gt;&gt; No, I that's it basically is your BMI
不，基本上就是你的BMI
and your overall weight and must not
和总体重，而且不能
have a belly. Just don't have a belly.
有肚子。 只要没有大肚子就行。
If you have a belly, you have a problem.
如果你有大肚子，那就说明你有问题了。
And what about my joints and stuff like
我的关节之类的部位怎么样了
that? Is that an indicator of
？ 这是否表明是的
&gt;&gt; Yes, if you have joint now symptoms, if
，如果你现在有关节症状，如果
you're having joint pains, look, if
你感到关节疼痛，你看，如果
you're having joint pains, people think,
你感到关节疼痛，人们会想，
"Oh, it's just degenerative joint
“哦，这只是退行性关节
disease." In my experience, what I have
疾病。” 以我的经验和
seen, it's all inflammation. Because
所见，都是炎症。 因为
when I change the diet, when I fix the
当我改变饮食习惯，当我解决
gut issues, when I fix the inflammation
肠道问题，当我消除
in the body, they all come back and say
体内的炎症时，他们都会回来告诉我
the joints got better. All of them
关节好转了。 它们都
uniformly. Especially patients who have
一样。 尤其是患有
autoimmune disease.
自身免疫性疾病的患者。
For example, many patients have
例如，许多患有
rheumatoid and the moment we change
类风湿性关节炎的患者，一旦我们改变
their diet, their lifestyle, the
他们的饮食、生活方式、
frequencies of eating, introduce a
进食频率，引入一些
little bit of fasting. So, we do
禁食措施，病情就会有所改善。 所以，我们做的
everything right. Right. We've changed
一切都是正确的。 正确的。 我们改变了
the gut microbiome. We've we've made the
肠道微生物群。 我们通过
liver better by by by giving them some
给他们补充一些营养品，改善了他们的肝脏状况
supplements. We do intermittent fasting,
。 我们让他们进行间歇性禁食，
we do some exercises, we give them some
做一些运动，给他们一些
stress management, we improve their
压力管理方法，改善他们的
sleep. All of a sudden the joint pains
睡眠。 突然间，关节疼痛
get better, rheumatoid gets better, skin
减轻了，类风湿病减轻了，
diseases get better, psoriasis gets
皮肤病减轻了，银屑病
better because it's the fundamental
减轻了，因为所有这些疾病的根本原因都是
underlying part is all inflammation.
炎症。
&gt;&gt; This is a random one, but I'm just
这是一个随机的话题，但我只是把
guests I've had on the show. What about
我节目中不同播客嘉宾的观点联系起来。 那
bad breath?
口臭呢？
&gt;&gt; Bad breath. Bad breath is real.
口臭。 口臭是真实存在的。
&gt;&gt; But what is it? Is my oral microbiome
但它究竟是什么？ 我的口腔微生物群
linked to my heart health?
与我的心脏健康有关吗？   是的
&gt;&gt; Yes. There's a there's a microbiome that
。 人体内存在一个微生物群，它
goes all the way from your nose, mouth,
从你的鼻子、嘴巴一直
all the way down to the anus. And each
延伸到肛门。 每
one is specific and can predict whether
一种都有其特殊性，可以预测
you're going to get cardiovascular
你是否会患上心血管
disease or not. There's unequivocal data
疾病。 有确凿的数据
to show that if you have bad teeth, bad
表明，如果你牙齿不好、
dental hygiene, bad bacteria in your
口腔卫生差、口腔内有有害细菌
mouth, you're going to get valvular
，你就会患上瓣膜
disease such as aotic stenosis,
疾病，例如主动脉瓣狭窄、
premature calcification of your aotic
主动脉瓣过早钙化
valve, and you're going to get coronary
，而且你还会患上冠状动脉
calcification. That's been proven
钙化。 这一点已经得到了
unequivocally. Patients who have chronic
无可辩驳的证明。 你认为患有慢性鼻窦炎的患者
that's benign? If you have chronic
是良性的吗？ 如果你患有慢性
sinusitis,
鼻窦炎，那么
&gt;&gt; what's chronic sinusitis?
什么是慢性鼻窦炎？
&gt;&gt; Chronic sinusitis, infections inside
慢性鼻窦炎，
your maxural sinuses, frontal sinuses
上颌窦、额窦内部
constantly and you get these headaches
不断感染，你会头痛、
and and you get the cold and your block
感冒、
nose and you constantly cog up inside
鼻塞，而且你的身体内部总是感觉不舒服
here. That's inflammation. And often
。 那是炎症。 而且，这种情况往往
times that's also linked to premature
还与过早发生
coronary artery disease and inflammation
冠状动脉疾病和
in your body. Especially when it's
体内炎症有关。 尤其是
fungal. There's a condition called
真菌感染的时候。 有一种疾病叫做
fungal sinusitis. Again it comes down to
真菌性鼻窦炎。 归根结底还是
mold. And this mold it causes that
霉菌的问题。 这种霉菌会导致
lowgrade inflammation in your body. And
你体内出现低度炎症。 而
this has been linked to coronary artery
这与冠状动脉
disease. See what's happening is we
疾病有关。 我们现在正在做的，是彻底
transforming the whole definition of the
改变
causes of coronary artery disease. We
冠状动脉疾病病因的定义。 我们
have been so myopic in our definition of
对冠状动脉疾病病因的定义一直非常短视，
whereas everything your entire lif style
而事实上，你的整个生活方式，包括
mental physical eating everything will
精神、身体、饮食等等，都会
affect your coronary arteries everything
影响你的冠状动脉。
&gt;&gt; do you think much about
你有没有认真考虑过
over stimulation so I mean really mean
过度刺激？我的意思是，真的，比如摄入
much caffeine play a role and I say this
过多的咖啡因，它真的会起作用吗？我这么说
in part because I think there's been a
部分原因是，我觉得有好
few times where I've had like a pre-work
几次，我在上班前
workout or too many glasses of coffee
锻炼或者喝了太多咖啡后，出现了
and I've got like heart palpitations and
心悸，
you almost like feel like you're dying.
感觉自己快要死了。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yes. Yes. Yes. Caffeine. Caffeine is
。 是的。 是的。 咖啡因。 咖啡因
very similar to the adrenaline molecule.
与肾上腺素分子非常相似。
Now, why would you want to have too much
那么，你为什么要让
adrenaline in your body? Because then
体内肾上腺素过多呢？ 因为那样的话，
you're living in a state of existential
你就一直生活在生存
threat constantly and then what happens?
威胁之中，然后会发生什么呢？
You don't get the offset either. So, you
你也无法获得偏移量。 所以，你
don't get the parasympathetic. You're
不会感受到副交感神经的作用。 你一直都只是
only in sympathetic all the time.
同情而已。
&gt;&gt; all the time. So caffeine generates that
时刻处于战斗或逃跑状态。 所以咖啡因会产生这种效果，从
and the physiology it'll look caffeine
生理角度来看，咖啡因似乎
is not as benign as we think it is. Now
并不像我们想象的那样无害。
two coffees a day. That's fine. Okay.
一天喝一两杯咖啡没什么问题。 没关系。 好的。
But I know people who drink about six
但我认识一些人一天要喝六
glasses or six cups of coffee a day and
杯咖啡，
and I think that that's just that's
我认为这简直就是
toxicity. You see that's toxicity. Too
有害的。 你看，这就是毒性。
much caffeine. And it's a diuretic. And
咖啡因摄入过量。 而且它还是一种利尿剂。
a diuretic will cause intravascular
利尿剂会导致血管内
volume depletion and that also turns on
血容量减少，这也会
your neuro hormonal activation. So you
激活神经激素。 于是你
become more sympathetic. You see? So
变得更有同情心了。 你看？ 所以
it's a vicious cycle makes you
这是一个恶性循环，会导致
dehydrated.
脱水。
&gt;&gt; I was reading about this earlier cuz I
我之前看过一些相关的资料，因为有
day because I think I drank too much
一天我出现了心悸，我觉得可能是
coffee. Um and what I what I see here in
咖啡喝多了。 嗯，我从
the research says that moderate caffeine
研究中看到的是，适量的咖啡因
is safe and even heart protective for
对大多数人来说是安全的，甚至对心脏有保护作用
most people. But excessive caffeine when
。 但是，如果每天
you get, you know, above 600 milligrams
摄入超过 600 毫克的咖啡因，
um can raise blood pressure, trigger
就会升高血压，引发
&gt;&gt; arrhythmias.
心律失常。
&gt;&gt; Arhrihythmias and stress the heart. Yes.
心律失常和心脏压力。 是的。
Now, I want to tell you why coffee is
现在，我想告诉你们为什么咖啡
good. It's not good because of the
好。 因为含有
caffeine. And so, it's not good that,
咖啡因，所以不好。 所以，认为“
oh, I'm getting that caffeine, so it's
哦，我摄入了咖啡因，所以这
good for me. No, cuz believe it or not,
对我有好处”这种想法是不对的。 不，因为信不信由你，
coffee has a lot of soluble fiber in it.
咖啡里含有大量的可溶性纤维。
So, there is some soluble fiber in it
所以，它含有一些可溶性纤维
and it has polyphenols.
和多酚。
So, coffee has polyphenols just like how
所以，咖啡含有多酚，就像可可
cocoa has, you know, cocoa, cacao, 85%
含有多酚一样，你知道，可可，可可粉，85%可可含量的
cacao, chocolate, that's fantastic. It's
巧克力，那真是太棒了。 它
got soluble fiber cuz who's going to
含有可溶性纤维，但谁会
consume the soluble fiber? It's actually
去吃可溶性纤维呢？ 其实是
the bacteria. So a coffee a day is
细菌。 所以，每天一杯咖啡对
actually good for you for a different
你的好处其实另有
reason. It's good because it's good for
隐情。 它的好处在于它对
your bacteria because it's getting
你的细菌有益，因为它能
soluble fiber and it's getting
提供可溶性纤维和
polyphenols and all those polyphenols
多酚，而所有这些多酚都会被
are consumed by your bacteria.
你的细菌消耗掉。
&gt;&gt; They they call cacao, don't they? The
他们把可可叫做可可，对吧？
something of the heart. My girlfriend's
内心深处的东西。 我女朋友
quite spiritual and in her practice they
很注重精神层面，在她的修行中，
call it like the heart medicine. Cacao.
这被称为心灵疗愈。 可可。
&gt;&gt; Cacao. It is because it has a lot of
可可。 这是因为它含有大量的
antioxidants and it has a lot of soluble
抗氧化剂和可溶性
fiber. So wait a second. It's a soluble
纤维。 稍等片刻。 它是一种可溶性
fiber. Yes, because that's fostering the
纤维。 是的，因为那样可以促进
growth of the good microbiome. The good
有益微生物群的生长。 良好的
microbiome is then going to produce
微生物群会产生
postbiotics and the postbiotics are
后生元，而后生元
going to give you all the benefit that
会给你带来
you're going to need. So, it's going to
你所需的所有益处。 所以，这样可以
cause less leaky gut, less inflammation
减少肠漏，减少炎症，保护
and your entic nervous system, your
你的迷走神经系统，因为
vagus nerve, your vag nerve is going to
你的迷走神经会受到
be protected because we're destroying
保护，因为我们
our vag nerve right now with the leaky
现在正因为肠漏而破坏我们的迷走神经
gut. When people get heart palpitations,
。 我想很多人在出现心悸症状时都会给
I imagine a lot of them message you
你发信息，
because it's quite scary, isn't it, when
因为这很可怕，不是吗？当
you feel your heart beating,
你感觉到自己的心脏在跳动时，
what is typically going on and when is
通常会发生什么？
it cause for concern if you've got heart
如果出现
palpitations?
心悸，什么时候需要引起重视？   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah. If you have underlying structural
。 如果你患有潜在的结构性
heart disease, let's say you have
心脏病，比如
blocked arteries, let's say you have a
动脉阻塞、
cardiopathy, a valvular disease, and
心脏病、瓣膜疾病，并且
you're having an arrhythmia, which is
出现心律失常（即
palpitations, that is definitely
心悸），那绝对是
life-threatening. They need to come
危及生命的。 他们需要
straight to the office and we need to
直接来办公室，我们需要
monitor you and find out what's going
监视你，查明发生了什么事
on. But let's say you're otherwise
。 但假设你身体
perfectly healthy, young person,
非常健康，你是一个年轻人，身体
perfectly healthy, no heart disease
非常健康，没有
whatsoever, and you're having
任何心脏病，却出现了
palpitations, then it's usually an
心悸，那么这通常是
imbalance of your sympathetic and
你的交感神经和
parasympathetic nervous system. You're
副交感神经系统失衡的表现。 你
too stressed.
压力太大了。
&gt;&gt; It's basically either too much
基本上要么是
sympathetic or not too much sympathetic,
交感神经功能过强，要么是交感神经功能不足
but you have too little parasympathetic.
但副交感神经功能过弱。
And that is one thing that I want people
我想让人们
to realize that if you've knocked your
意识到的一点是，如果你因为
gut or because of your lifestyle and
肠漏症或不良生活方式而导致迷走神经受损，迷
your vagus nerve is not working very
走神经功能
well, you will have this imbalance
不佳，就会出现这种失衡，
because the imbalance is not with
因为这种失衡并非
absolute levels. It's the relative
绝对水平上的失衡。 这是
levels of sympathetic versus
交感神经与
parasympathetic. So for example, I see a
副交感神经的相对水平。 例如，我看到
lot of young women in their 30s and 20s
很多 20 多岁和 30 多岁的年轻女性因为
who come to me with tachicardia. They
心动过速来找我。 他们一直
have a rapid heartbeat all the time and
心跳很快，
especially when they stand up, they get
尤其是站起来的时候，
a rapid heartbeat. This is called
心跳会更快。 这被称为
postural orthostatic tachicardia. And
体位性心动过速。
when they come to me, I find out that
当他们来找我时，我发现问题
it's actually the gut. I fix their gut
其实出在肠胃上。 我治好了他们的肠道
and the tachicardia gets better because
，心动过速的情况就好转了，因为
by fixing the gut, I'm fixing the vagus
通过治好肠道，我就治好了迷走
nerve. By fixing the vagus nerve, the
神经。 通过修复迷走神经，
heart rates come down.
心率会下降。
&gt;&gt; I've built companies from scratch and
我曾白手起家创办公司，也
backed many more. And there's a blind
投资过许多其他公司。
spot that I keep seeing in early stage
我发现早期
founders. They spend very little time
创业者身上存在一个盲点。 他们很少花时间
thinking about HR. And it's not because
考虑人力资源问题。 这并非因为
they're reckless or they don't care.
他们鲁莽或漠不关心。
It's because they're obsessed with
这是因为他们一心只想
building their companies. And I can't
发展自己的公司。 我对此并不
fault them for that. At that stage,
责怪他们。 到了那个阶段，
you're thinking about the product. How
你考虑的是产品。 如何
to attract new customers, how to grow
吸引新客户，如何发展
your team, really how to survive. And HR
团队，以及如何生存下去。 而人力资源事务
slips down the list because it doesn't
则被排在了后面，因为它
feel urgent. But sooner or later, it is.
感觉并不紧急。 但迟早会是这样。
And when things get messy, tools like
当事情变得一团糟时，像
our sponsor today, Just Works, go from
我们今天的赞助商 Just Works 这样的工具，就从
being a nice to have to being a
锦上添花了变成了
necessity. Something goes sideways and
必不可少。 事情出了岔子，
you find yourself having conversations
你发现自己陷入了
you did not see coming. This is when you
意想不到的对话中。 这时你才会
learn that HR really is the
明白，人力资源部门才是
infrastructure of your company and
公司的真正基础设施，
without it things wobble and Just work
没有它，公司就会摇摇欲坠。而“只管干活”却不会让
stops you learning this the hard way. It
你通过惨痛的教训明白这一点。 它可以自动
takes care of the stuff that would
处理那些原本会
otherwise drain your energy and your
耗费您大量精力和
time automating payroll, health
时间的事情，例如工资单、医疗
insurance benefits and it gives your
保险福利等，并且随时为您的
team human support at any hour. It grows
团队提供人工支持。 它能
with your small business from startup
伴随您的小型企业从初创
through to growth even when you start
到发展壮大，甚至在您开始在
hiring team members abroad. So if you
海外招聘团队成员时也能持续成长。 因此，如果您
want HR support that's there through the
想要在
exciting times and the challenging times
激动人心的时刻和充满挑战的时刻都能获得人力资源支持，请
head to justworks.com now. That's
立即访问 justworks.com。 那是
justworks.com.
justworks.com。
I've just invested millions into this
我刚刚向这家公司投资了数百万美元，
and become a co-owner of the company.
并成为其共同所有人。
It's a company called Ketone IQ. And the
这是一家名为 Ketone IQ 的公司。 这个
story is quite interesting. I started
故事很有意思。 我
talking about ketosis on this podcast
在播客里开始谈论生酮饮食，
and the fact that I'm very low carb,
以及我摄入的碳水化合物和糖分非常非常少
very, very low sugar, and my body
，我的身体会
produces ketones, which have made me
产生酮体，这让我
incredibly focused, have improved my
注意力非常集中，提高了我的
endurance, have improved my mood, and
耐力，改善了我的情绪，也
have made me more capable at doing what
让我更有能力做好
I do here. And because I was talking
我在这里做的事情。 因为我在
about it on the podcast, a couple of
播客节目中谈到了这件事，
weeks later, these showed up on my desk
几周后，
in my HQ in London, these little shots.
这些小照片就出现在我伦敦总部的办公桌上。
And oh my god, the impact this had on my
天哪，它对我的
ability to articulate myself, on my
表达能力、
focus, on my workouts, on my mood, on
专注力、锻炼效果、情绪以及
stopping me crashing throughout the day
防止我一天中情绪崩溃的影响
was so profound that I reached out to
如此深远，以至于我联系了
the founders of the company, and now I'm
公司的创始人，现在我成了
a co-owner of this business. I highly,
这家公司的共同所有人。 我强烈
highly recommend you look into this. I
建议你调查一下这件事。 我
highly recommend you look at the science
强烈建议你了解一下
behind the product. If you want to try
该产品背后的科学原理。 如果您想
it for yourself, visit
亲自尝试一下，请访问
ketone.com/stephven
ketone.com/stephven，
for 30% off your subscription order. And
订阅订单可享 30% 的折扣。 而且，
you'll also get a free gift with your
您的第二批货物还会附赠一份免费礼物
second shipment. That's
。 那是
ketone.com/stephven.
ketone.com/stephven。
And I'm so honored that once again, a
我非常荣幸，
company I own can sponsor my podcast.
我拥有的公司能够再次赞助我的播客节目。   那我们就来
Let's talk about the V Vegas nerve then.
聊聊拉斯维加斯的V神经吧。
Um before we do that, I had a little a
嗯，在那之前，我得先说一件
little incident actually caused by
小事，其实是
Jamaima who's out there. Jamaima We were
Jamaima 引起的，她现在就在外面。 贾迈玛：我们参加了一个
in this little fitness competition and
小型健身比赛，
Jamaima decided that she wanted to beat
贾迈玛决定要赢过
me and so she cycled 100 kilometers one
我，于是有一天她骑行了 100 公里
day. She cycled for 4 hours which meant
。 她骑行了 4 个小时，这意味着
that she had more minutes in this
她在这次
fitness competition than I did. So my
健身比赛中比我坚持的时间更长。 所以我的
rebuttal was to do the same but more. So
反驳方式是做同样的事情，但做得更多。
the next day I cycled just over 100 km
第二天，我
on my Pelaton at home. Funny enough, it
在家骑着我的 Peloton 自行车骑行了 100 多公里。 说来也怪，我居然花了
took me like 4 hours to do it. And then
四个小时才完成。 然后
I came off the Pelaton. I was
我就退出了Peloton车队。 我当时在
celebrating whatever, you know, won this
庆祝，你知道，我赢得了这个
gold medal emoji as my reward that
金牌表情符号作为当月的奖励
month, but also I won heart palpitations
，但同时我也赢得了持续了
that stayed with me for a little while.
一段时间的心悸。
And I was wondering like why that
我当时就在想，为什么会
happened. So I did this big vigorous
发生这种事。 所以我做了一次强度很大的
exercise which was kind of outside of my
运动，这有点超出了我
usual exercise regime and then for a a
平时的运动计划，然后接下来的几个
couple of weeks I could like feel these
星期，我能感觉到
heart pulpitations
心脏有搏动感，这是
and is that because of what you were
因为你之前
saying about my parasympathetic?
说的关于我的副交感神经的事情吗？
What do you think happened there?
你觉得那里发生了什么事？   是的
&gt;&gt; Yes. Yes. Yes. Yes. over exercise.
。 是的。 是的。 是的。 运动过度。
This has been shown when you do what you
事实证明，当你做你
just did, you're diverting blood from
刚才做的事情时，你是在将血液从
your gut to your muscles because your
肠道转移到肌肉，因为此时你的
muscles at that point really need all
肌肉确实需要所有的
that blood supply. And this has been
血液供应。 这一点已有
well documented. So what happens when
充分的文献记载。 那么，像
you overly exercise like that? You're
这样过度运动会发生什么呢？ 你正在
causing relative eskeeia to your gut.
对你的肠道造成相对的埃斯基亚氏病。
Essia. Essia. What does eskeemia mean?
埃西亚。 埃西亚。  eskeemia是什么意思？
Lack of circulation to your gut. So your
肠道血液循环不良。 所以当时你的
poor gut at that point had lack of
肠道血液
circulation relative. Not to the point
循环相对不足。 还没到会发展成
where it's going to go gangrous. No,
坏疽的地步。 不，
don't don't get me wrong. But it affects
别误会我的意思。 但这会影响
your gut and in the gut is the entic
你的肠道，而肠道内有
nervous system. The vagus nerve ends in
神经系统。 迷走神经末端位于
your gut lining and the vagus nerve got
肠道内壁，迷走神经受到了
affected. So your vagus nerve didn't
影响。 所以你的迷走神经功能不太
work very well. When you get vagus nerve
好。 迷走神经功能
not working well, you get too much
不佳时，会导致
sympathetic. You're going to get
交感神经过度活跃。 你会出现
tachicardia. You're going to get
心动过速。 你会出现
arrhythmias, palpitations. So tell me
心律失常和心悸。 那么请告诉我
what the vagus nerve is and what I can
迷走神经是什么，以及我该如何控制
do to get my vagus nerve in check. By
我的迷走神经。 对
the way, Jamaima, it was totally worth
了，贾迈玛，这完全值得
it. But just tell me what I what I can
。 但请告诉我，我该如何克服在
do to get my Vegas nerve in check and
拉斯维加斯的紧张情绪，以及这种紧张情绪在
like what role my Vegas nerve plays.
拉斯维加斯扮演着怎样的角色。
I've got this photo here of the Vegas
我这里有一张拉斯维加斯
nerve.
神经的照片。
&gt;&gt; Yeah, you know, the Vegas nerve is
是啊，你知道，拉斯维加斯的神经真是
fascinating.
令人着迷。
It is the largest nerve in the body
它是人体最大的神经，它
and it it it basically is sending
基本上负责将
messages from the brain to the whole
信息从大脑传递到
body and receiving messages back to say
全身，并接收反馈信息来判断
what is the state of affairs and the
身体状况。
largest distribution believe it or not
信不信由你，它最大的分布区域就
is all in your gut. Now that tells you
在你的肠道里。 这正好说明了
what is the brain most concerned about?
大脑最关心的是什么？
It's most concerned about the most
它最关注的是
treacherous border in your body which is
你体内最危险的边界——
your gut.
你的肠道。
Your gut health is so important that the
肠道健康非常重要，以至于
body has dedicated a huge nerve called
人体专门有一条叫做
the vagus nerve just to take care of
迷走神经的巨大神经来照顾
your gut because your gut is that
肠道，因为肠道就是这么
important. That is why by the way it
重要。 所以，顺便说一句，它在
also has endings on the heart in your
心脏、肺部和脸上也有末端
lungs in your face. So there's lots of
。
endings of the vagus nerve
迷走神经有很多末梢，它们的作用
&gt;&gt; and what is it doing? Is it telling is
是什么呢？ 这是否说明
it basically the communication channel
它基本上是
between all your gut, your heart, your
你内心、情感和
brain
大脑
&gt;&gt; state of affairs? What is going on in
状态之间的沟通渠道？ 肠道里发生了什么
the gut? What should I be doing? Back
？ 我应该怎么做？
and forth traffic information going back
交通信息来回
and forth. So when you when you the body
传递。 所以，当你……的时候，身体
is supposed to be in a state of
应该处于
sympathetic followed by parasympathetic.
交感神经兴奋状态，然后是副交感神经兴奋状态。
&gt;&gt; What does that mean?
这意味着什么？
&gt;&gt; You run away from the tiger. You hide
你逃离了老虎。 你躲在
behind the rock. The tiger is gone now
岩石后面。 老虎已经走了，
and now you're supposed to be
现在你应该处于副
parasympathetic.
交感神经兴奋状态。   这场
&gt;&gt; So sympathetic is the fight.
斗争如此令人同情。
Parasympathetic is the the relaxation,
副交感神经负责放松、
&gt;&gt; rest, relaxation, repair. Guess what?
休息、修复。 你猜怎么着？
We're not getting enough repair these
如今我们得不到足够的修复，
days because we constantly in the fight
因为我们总是处于战斗或逃跑的应激状态
flight fight. We never give our chance
。 我们从不给
to go into repair. That's what the
维修的机会。 这就是
problem with the Vegas nerve that we
我们今天在拉斯维加斯遇到的问题所在
have today is. So we don't get a chance.
。 所以我们没有机会。
So that is why don't we do it? Well, one
所以这就是我们不做这件事的原因吗？ 首先
is our lifestyle. Two, our gut is not
是我们的生活方式。 第二，我们的肠道出了问题，
right because it has disade our vagus
因为它导致我们的迷走
nerve dysfunctional. When I fix the gut,
神经功能紊乱。 当我调理好肠道后，
one of the things I notice is heart rate
我注意到的一件事是心率
variability gets better. What does that
变异性有所改善。 这
mean? Heart rate variability. That means
意味着什么？ 心率变异性。 这意味着
your pulse with each breath in and each
每次吸气和呼气时，你的脉搏都会略有
breath out, there's a little variation
变化，
in your heartbeat. H that's called heart
心跳也会略有波动。 那叫做
rate variability. Now, when you lost
心率变异性。 现在，当
your heart rate variability, it means
你的心率变异性消失时，意味着
that your vagus nerve is not working
你的迷走神经功能不太
very well. In all patients when I fix
好。 在所有患者中，当我修复
the gut the heart rate variability gets
肠道问题后，心率变异性也会得到
better as well. When you fix the gut
改善。 当你修复了肠道后，
your vagus nerve will be able to work
你的迷走神经就能
more efficiently and you'll be able to
更有效地工作，你就能
repair yourself after the sympathetic
在交感神经兴奋后进行自我修复
drive. So you get the ying and then you
。 所以你既得到了阴，也
get the yang as well. And the nice thing
得到了阳。
about the vagus nerve that I find is
我发现迷走神经的好处在于，
that you can repair it through the gut
你可以通过肠道修复它，也
but you can also hack it and you can
可以通过一些方法削弱它，还可以
give it some nutritional supplements.
给它补充一些营养。
The nutritional supplements are omega-3
营养补充剂是 omega-3，
which right now 50% of the population is
目前 50% 的人口
very low in omega-3 and you need DHA and
omega-3 含量非常低，而 DHA 和
omega-3 to to to make their vag nerve
omega-3 是使阴道神经发挥
work optimally. You need to fix the gut
最佳功能的必要条件。 你需要先调理肠道，
and thirdly you can hack the vagus
第三，你可以干扰迷走
nerve. So how do you do that? You do the
神经。 那么该怎么做呢？ 你做
breathing exercises. So when you do the
呼吸练习。 所以当你
deep expiration, you stimulate all those
深呼气时，你会刺激所有副
parasympathetic nerve endings and your
交感神经末梢，你的
heart rate goes down, blood pressure
心率就会下降，血压也会
goes down.
下降。
&gt;&gt; What kind of breathing exercises?
什么样的呼吸练习？
&gt;&gt; So breathe in to the count of four,
吸气数到四，
breathe out to the count of eight. Very
呼气数到八。 非常
simple. I tell that to all my patients.
简单。 我把这话告诉了所有病人。
Breathe in to the count of four. Breathe
吸气，数到四。 呼气，数
out to the count of eight. It's a
到八。 这是一个
deliberately long expression. You do
故意写得很长的表达方式。 你
that for about 10 minutes a day.
每天这样做大约10分钟。
And when you do that, your vagus nerve
当你这样做时，你的迷走神经
is getting stimulated. And any nerve
就会受到刺激。 任何神经如果
that is stimulated frequently enough
经常受到刺激，
will work more efficiently.
都会更有效地工作。
&gt;&gt; What about this eyeball thing that I've
我
heard you talk about where you
听你说过
&gt;&gt; eyeball does affect the vagus nerve
眼球也会影响迷走神经
function too. So when you look to the
功能，你觉得怎么样？ 所以当你向右看
right, look to the left at the top, look
、向左上方看、
down, look left, it stimulates the vagus
向下看、向左看时，就会刺激迷走
nerve. There's a nerve on the ear.
神经。 耳朵上有一条神经。
stimulated here in the neck that can be
颈部的迷走神经也可以受到
stimulated. The facial nerve also uh has
刺激。 面神经也有
branches that go to the vagus nerve. So
分支通往迷走神经。 所以
there are a few hacks that people can
有一些技巧可以
use. I even have a small contraption
使用。 我甚至还有一个小装置，可以
that I give patients that wear around
给病人戴在
the neck and it it it releases little
脖子上，它会向
signals onto the vagus nerve over here
这里的迷走神经释放一些信号。
and I've placed it on patients and they
我把它放在病人身上，让他们在我
in front of me and they'll say, "Oh my
面前体验，他们会说：“哦，我的
god, I really feel so relaxed and nice."
天哪，我真的感觉很放松很舒服。”
And it's I was shocked when they did
他们这么做的时候，我感到非常震惊
that. I heard you talk about massaging
。 我听你说过要按摩
the eyeball.
眼球。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yes. And cold water on the eyeballs. So,
。 用冷水冲洗眼睛。 所以，
I don't advise massaging too often, but
我不建议经常按摩，但用
cold water and gentle massage on your
冷水轻轻按摩
eyeballs stimulates the vagus nerve. And
眼球可以刺激迷走神经。 而且
you can do it yourself. You'll notice
你可以自己动手。 你会注意到，
that if you're on a monoton, you do
如果你的生活单调乏味
that, your pulse rate goes down. It's
，你的脉搏就会下降。 这是
the deep dive reflex that we have in all
我们每个人身上都存在的深潜反射
of us. We dive into water.
。 我们跳入水中。
&gt;&gt; What about putting an ice pack on the
要不试试在脖子后面敷个冰袋
back of your neck?
？
&gt;&gt; I think that's fantastic. Back of the
我觉得这太棒了。 脖子后面
neck, but I prefer the front of the
，但我更喜欢
neck. Okay.
脖子前面。 好的。
&gt;&gt; Because the front of the neck is closed.
因为领口前面是封闭的。
The vagus nerve is very close to the
迷走神经
karate sheath over here. And when you
在这里离空手道鞘很近。 当你用
put ice packs on it, the vagus nerve is
冰袋敷在上面时，迷走神经就会
stimulated.
受到刺激。
&gt;&gt; Humming for 10 minutes.
哼唱10分钟。
&gt;&gt; 10 minutes. Both sides.
10分钟。 双方。
&gt;&gt; What do you mean by humming? Give me an
你说的哼唱是什么意思？ 请举个
example.
例子。
&gt;&gt; Oh, humming. Oh, humming. Oh, yeah. That
哦，哼歌。 哦，哼歌。 哦，是的。 那个
sound is transmitted
声音会传递
to the vagus nerve. So, it's like
到迷走神经。 所以，这就像
shaking that vagus nerve and it creates
摇晃迷走神经，从而在
electrical impulses uh in the vagus
迷走神经中产生电脉冲
nerve. That's been shown. Singing,
。 这一点已经得到了证明。 唱歌，
singing, singing. humming,
唱歌，唱歌。 哼着歌，
&gt;&gt; laughing.
笑着。
&gt;&gt; You know that there are laughing clubs.
你知道有笑声俱乐部吗？
&gt;&gt; Maybe you should start a laughing club.
或许你应该成立一个笑声俱乐部。
&gt;&gt; Laughing clubs. Yeah, laugh for no
笑声俱乐部。 是啊，无缘无故地笑
reason. Just sit there and laugh. So
。 你就坐在那儿笑吧。 因此
that diaphragmatic movement, that
，笑
constant diaphragmatic movement in
时膈肌的持续运动会
laughing stimulates the vagus nerve.
刺激迷走神经。
&gt;&gt; I heard you talk about this valva
我听你谈起过这个瓣膜
maneuver.
操作。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
。   那
&gt;&gt; What's that?
是什么？
&gt;&gt; The valva is when you breathe in
呼吸困难是指吸气
and then you breathe out, but don't let
后呼气，但无法将
the air out and you're straining. And
空气完全排出，导致呼吸困难。
that straining compresses the thoracic
这种用力不仅会压迫
cavity but also the abdominal cavity and
胸腔，还会压迫腹腔，并
stimulates the vagus nerve. And that is
刺激迷走神经。 而且这
also found to be very very helpful.
也被证明非常非常有用。
&gt;&gt; And remind me again if I have a healthy
请再次提醒我，如果我的迷
vagus nerve, if I have a calm healthy
走神经健康，如果我的迷
vagus nerve, what is the downstream
走神经处于平静健康的状态，那么这对
impact going to be across my life?
我的人生会有怎样的后续影响？
&gt;&gt; Downstream impact is going to be faster
下游影响将是伤口
healing,
愈合更快、
less coronary disease, less high blood
冠心病发病率更低、高血压
pressure. Your blood will not be so
发病率更低。 你的血液不会那么
sticky and make blood clots less
粘稠，血栓也会减少，
inflammatory markers.
炎症标志物也会减少。
The blood tests that we do, the
我们做的血液检查，包括
interucan 6, the tumor necrosis factor,
Interucan 6、肿瘤坏死因子、
the CRP levels, small dense LDL, we
CRP 水平、小而密的 LDL，我们
didn't even talk about LDL, but LDL, the
甚至都没谈到 LDL，但 LDL，也就是
bad cholesterol, all those get better.
坏胆固醇，所有这些都会好转。
&gt;&gt; And what is the the the role of LDL as
低密度脂蛋白（LDL）在心脏病中扮演着怎样的角色
it relates to heart disease? Because
？ 因为
I've heard this word cholesterol. I
我听说过胆固醇这个词。 我
really don't really understand what it
真的不太明白那是什么
is. or I know there's good cholesterol,
。 或者说，我知道胆固醇有
there's bad cholesterol. I I guess that
好坏之分。 我猜想
bad cholesterol comes from fast food and
坏胆固醇来源于快餐和
processed foods and stuff, but simply
加工食品等等，但
what do I need to understand about the
我需要了解
role cholesterol plays in heart disease
胆固醇在心脏病中所起的作用
and how to not have bad cholesterol?
以及如何避免坏胆固醇呢？
&gt;&gt; The LDL car carries most of the
低密度脂蛋白胆固醇（LDL）携带
cholesterol in the body. It's not
体内大部分胆固醇。 这并不
complicated.
复杂。
&gt;&gt; LDL is what
LDL是什么？
&gt;&gt; is LDL is a lipoprotein.
LDL是一种脂蛋白。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
。
&gt;&gt; Right. And you have HDL which is good
正确的。 而且你体内还有高密度脂蛋白（HDL），也就是好
cholesterol. LDL, bad cholesterol, total
胆固醇。 低密度脂蛋白胆固醇（坏胆固醇）、总
cholesterol and triglycerides. Okay,
胆固醇和甘油三酯。 好的，
these are the four tests.
这就是四项测试。
&gt;&gt; So the LDL is a reflection of your
所以，低密度脂蛋白胆固醇（LDL）反映的是你的
cholesterol. Now cholesterol is a normal
胆固醇水平。 胆固醇是人
molecule in your body and you should
体内的正常分子，人体应该
have cholesterol because if you don't
含有胆固醇，因为如果
have cholesterol, I don't think you live
没有胆固醇，我认为你活不了
too long and you need to move this
多久，而且人体需要将
cholesterol around your body. Every cell
胆固醇输送到身体各处。 人体每个细胞都会
in the body makes cholesterol. Your
产生胆固醇。 实际上，
liver makes most of the cholesterol
大部分胆固醇都是由肝脏产生的
actually. Now what happens is that when
。 现在的情况是，当
that LDL molecule becomes damaged, it
低密度脂蛋白分子受损时，它会
becomes a small dense LDL particle. A
变成一个体积小、密度高的低密度脂蛋白颗粒。
damaged LDL causes inflammation because
受损的低密度脂蛋白会引起炎症，因为
now you have a molecule that's floating
现在体内有这种分子在游离
around your body. It's been damaged.
。 它被损坏了。
It's small. It's dense. Now your white
它很小。 它很稠密。 现在你的
cells, your macrofasages see that and
白细胞，你的大纤维细胞看到了这一点，并
want to gobble it up. That's number one.
想要将其吞噬。 这是第一点。
Number two, these molecules get oxidized
第二，这些分子
in the lungs and then they the first
在肺部被氧化，然后它们
place they come out from after the lungs
离开肺部后第一个排出体外的地方
is the coronary arteries. So it's the
是冠状动脉。 所以，这些
small dense LDL particles which are now
小而致密的低密度脂蛋白颗粒现在被
oxidized
氧化了，
they destroy the glycoalix which is the
它们破坏了
lining of the coronary arteries and they
冠状动脉内壁的糖脂，并
activate the endothelium.
激活了内皮细胞。
When they activate the endothelium which
当它们激活冠状动脉内壁的内皮细胞时，就会
that's when you're going to start
开始
getting aosclerosis. So atherosclerosis
出现动脉粥样硬化。 所以动脉粥样硬化
and LDL are related but it's not the the
和低密度脂蛋白胆固醇（LDL）有关，但与
total cholesterol. It's when you have
总胆固醇无关。 这种情况发生在你的低密度脂蛋白（
small dense damaged LDL. So let me
LDL）颗粒细小、密度高且受损的时候。 那么，让我来
explain the impact in my practice.
解释一下这对我的实践产生的影响。
Patients come to me because they either
患者来找我看病，要么是因为他们
cannot tolerate cholesterol medications
不能耐受降胆固醇药物，要么是因为
or they don't want to take cholesterol
他们不想服用降胆固醇
medications. What I do then is I look
药物。 然后我会查看
and say okay your LDL
并问：好的，你的低密度脂蛋白胆固醇（LDL）
is it high or low? Is it is that what
是高还是低？
I'm really concerned about or is it that
我真正担心的是这个，还是
it's small dense LDL? So I do a
小而密的低密度脂蛋白？ 所以我进行了
subfractionation and this is important
亚分馏，这一点
for you to understand because they don't
对你来说很重要，因为并不是
do it in every country in the world.
世界上每个国家都采用这种方法。   在
blood tests abroad. But in the United
国外很难做这些血液检查。 但在美国，这很
States is easy to do it. It's called
容易做到。 它被称为
subfraction of your LDL. So it tells you
低密度脂蛋白的亚组分。 它可以告诉你
whether you have small dense LDL or not.
你体内是否存在小而密的低密度脂蛋白胆固醇（LDL）。
So let's say you came to me and your LDL
假设你来找我，你的低密度脂蛋白胆固醇（LDL）
is 150. But if it's all made up of
是 150。但如果它全部由
large, fluffy, good, normal LDL, it's
大的、蓬松的、好的、正常的低密度脂蛋白胆固醇组成，那么它就
not going to be implicated in your
不会与你的
inflammation or in your coronary artery
炎症或冠状动脉
disease. I leave that alone. But if you
疾病有关。 我不打算再管这件事了。 但如果你体内
have small dense LDL, that also is a
有小而密的低密度脂蛋白，那也是个
problem because it's pointing me towards
问题，因为它表明存在
inflammation. Because what causes small,
炎症。 因为导致小而
dense, damaged LDL are glucose, omega6,
致密的受损低密度脂蛋白的原因是来自肠道的葡萄糖、ω-6脂肪酸、
advanced glycation end products, toxins,
晚期糖基化终产物、毒素
and lipopolyaccharides that come from
和脂多糖，也就是
the gut, leaky gut. So now I just gave
肠漏症。 刚才我给
you the primer
大家简单介绍了
for treating coronary artery disease.
冠状动脉疾病的治疗方法。
These five things
这五件事会
promote coronary artery disease and it's
促进冠状动脉疾病的发生，其中最重要的是
small dense LDL. Those macrofasages they
小而密的低密度脂蛋白胆固醇（LDL）。 这些大纤维束会
engulf small dense LDL and those
吞噬小而致密的低密度脂蛋白，这些
macrofasages become foam cells. The
大纤维束就会变成泡沫细胞。
endothelium has been already activated.
内皮细胞已被激活。
So they
所以它们会
bind to the endothelial lining.
与内皮细胞结合。
&gt;&gt; What's the endothelium?
什么是内皮？
&gt;&gt; The endothelium is the lining of the
内皮是
artery in your coronary artery. So these
冠状动脉内壁的一层组织。 所以这些
white cells that are full of fat, the
充满脂肪的白细胞，
bad fat attach themselves to it and then
坏脂肪会附着在上面，然后
become endothelialized. That means they
发生内皮化。 这意味着它们
become part of the wall.
成为了墙体的一部分。
&gt;&gt; So they become a plaque.
于是它们就变成了一块斑块。
&gt;&gt; That's now you got it. That's making the
现在你明白了吧。 那就是形成
plaque. You just hit it right on the
牙菌斑。 你真是说到点子上了
head.
。
&gt;&gt; So how would I naturally lower my LDL
那么，如何在
without taking statins or any of these
不服用他汀类药物或
other medications? Is there a way to to
其他药物的情况下，自然降低我的低密度脂蛋白胆固醇（LDL）呢？ 有没有
do it naturally?
自然的方法可以做到这一点？
&gt;&gt; You you stay away from from meat. Yes.
你远离肉类。 是的。
You've gone on a vegetarian diet. Yes,
你开始吃素了。 是的，
it'll come down. But there's no need to
它会倒塌的。 但没有必要，
&gt;&gt; or meat.
也没有肉。
&gt;&gt; Or meat because they'll all have
或者吃肉，因为它们都含有
cholesterol.
胆固醇。
&gt;&gt; Even chicken.
甚至包括鸡肉。
&gt;&gt; Even chicken. Yeah. If you want to bring
甚至包括鸡肉。 是的。 如果你想把它拆下来
it down. But the question is, do you
。 但问题是，你
really want to bring it down? Do you
真的想把它拆掉吗？ 你
really want to bring it down? Later. The
真的想把它拆掉吗？ 之后。
most recent data is very scary. It shows
最新数据非常可怕。 这表明，低密度
that patients who have the highest LDLs
脂蛋白胆固醇（LDL）水平最高的患者
actually make it into the '9s and live a
实际上可以达到 9 分之一以上，并过上更
healthier life. It's not the LDL, it's
健康的生活。 问题不在于低密度脂蛋白，而在于
the damaged LDL that's the problem. So
受损的低密度脂蛋白。 所以，
this the medical profession as a whole
这是整个医疗行业，
and all of us are having a problem
我们所有人都在努力应对的问题
grappling with this. Is it the total LDL
。
that we should be concerned about? Point
我们应该关注的是总低密度脂蛋白胆固醇（LDL）吗？ 请指出
to your question. What is a normal
您的问题。 什么是正常
cholesterol and should we be lowering
胆固醇？我们是否应该降低
cholesterol and the answer really is not
胆固醇？答案其实并不
that simple. What we should be doing is
那么简单。 我们应该
not to have small dense LDL. So the
避免产生小而密的低密度脂蛋白。 所以
question is that's the issue
问题是，这就是问题所在，
&gt;&gt; and small dense LDL five things. Sugar
以及小而密集的低密度脂蛋白胆固醇的五个方面。 糖是
causes it. Omega6,
罪魁祸首。  Omega6、
advanced glycation end products, toxins,
晚期糖基化终产物、毒素
and leaky gut. They make your
和肠漏症。 它们会使
cholesterol become small, dense
胆固醇变成细小、致密的
particles.
颗粒。
&gt;&gt; A lot of people are concerned about
很多人担心
eating eggs because they think it might
吃鸡蛋，因为他们认为鸡蛋可能会
raise their cholesterol levels.
升高胆固醇水平。
&gt;&gt; Absolutely no concerns whatsoever.
完全没有任何问题。
&gt;&gt; And what about statins? So a lot of
那么他汀类药物呢？ 所以很多
have heart related issues. Are they safe
有心脏问题的人都会被处方他汀类药物。
in the long run? Are they effective?
从长远来看，它们安全吗？ 它们有效吗？
&gt;&gt; Okay, first part, are they safe? For the
好的，首先，它们安全吗？
most part, they are. But at least 20 to
大多数情况下，确实如此。 但至少有 20% 到
30% of patients will suffer from
30% 的患者会患上
psychopenia which is loss of muscles. So
精神萎靡症，即肌肉萎缩。 所以
they'll get weakness, aches, pains.
他们会感到虚弱、疼痛。
They'll get diabetes because it causes
他们会患上糖尿病，因为它会导致
mitochondrial dysfunction. So they'll de
线粒体功能障碍。 所以他们会治疗
sugar problems and many of them also do
糖尿病，而且他们中的许多人还会治疗
developmental diseases. So I've seen
发育性疾病。 我发现
that they become forgetful and they just
他们变得健忘，
can't think right and I stop the statins
思维混乱，当我停用他汀类药物后，
and all of a sudden they start feeling
他们突然感觉
better. So no, not all statins are safe.
好多了。 所以，并非所有他汀类药物都是安全的。
You need to monitor statins also. They
你还需要监测他汀类药物的服用情况。 它们
can cause liver dysfunction. So you need
会导致肝功能障碍。 所以你需要
to watch that. Number two is that the
注意这一点。 第二点是，
statins are they effective. Effective in
他汀类药物是否有效。 在
what? If the end point is to reduce your
哪方面有效？ 如果最终目标是降低低密度脂蛋白
LDL. Yeah, statins will bring your LDL
胆固醇（LDL）。 是的，他汀类药物可以降低你的低密度脂蛋白胆固醇（LDL）
down. But does that translate to a
。 但这是否意味着
decrease in cardiovascular event rates?
心血管事件发生率的下降？
That's a totally different question. You
那完全是另一个问题。 你
see? So, is your goal just to reduce the
看？ 所以，你的目标仅仅是降低低密度
LDL or is your goal to reduce the
脂蛋白胆固醇（LDL）水平，还是降低
damaged, oxidized, small, dense LDL
受损的、氧化的、小而致密的低密度脂蛋白胆固醇（LDL）
levels? And when people say they have
水平？ 人们说自己患有
high blood pressure, that's because
高血压，那是因为
there's potentially a narrowing of their
他们的血管可能出现了狭窄
blood vessels. So, the the the blood has
。 所以，血液通过的
less space to go through. So, it's kind
空间就变小了。 所以，这有点像
of like squeezing a host pipe that it
挤压一根管道，让它
gets it gets shoots out faster. Is that
更快地喷出来。
typically what it means by high blood
高血压通常是指这个意思吗
pressure?
？
&gt;&gt; Sort of. Let me explain. When your
算是吧。 让我解释一下。 当你的
insulin levels are running high, all
胰岛素水平过高时，
your blood vessels and your capillaries
你所有的血管和毛细血管都
all don't vasoddilate properly.
无法正常扩张。
&gt;&gt; Oh, okay. And vasoddilation is the
哦好的。 血管舒张是指血管的
expansion and shrinking.
扩张和收缩。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah. So, they don't vasod dial
。 所以，他们的血管扩张功能无法
properly. So, you will get high blood
正常运作。 所以，你会得
pressure. So, one of the biggest things
高血压。 因此，
I've noticed with diabetes patients is
我注意到糖尿病患者最明显的一个现象是，
when I bring the insulin levels down
当我
through my fasting program and dietary
通过禁食疗法和饮食
changes, the blood pressures go away.
改变降低胰岛素水平时，他们的血压就会下降。
See, that's another thing that there's
你看，还有一点就是，根本
no such thing as essential hypertension.
不存在原发性高血压这种东西。
Essential hypertention meaning that you
原发性高血压，即
just have high blood pressure. There's
单纯的高血压。
always a cause. Either you have sleep
凡事皆有因果。 要么你患有睡眠
apnea or you have hyperinsulinemia
呼吸暂停症，要么你患有高胰岛素血症，
because sleep apnea also causes
因为睡眠呼吸暂停症也会导致
hypertension. So hypertension does not
高血压。 所以，高血压并不一定
always necessarily mean that you're
意味着你
medications for the rest of your life.
余生都需要服用降压药。
&gt;&gt; I've heard you talk quite a lot about
我听你说过很多次关于
breakfast. People ask you about what
早餐的事。 人们会问你
they should have for breakfast because
早餐应该吃什么，因为
everybody wants to know um how they
每个人都想知道他们
should be starting their day. What is
应该如何开始新的一天。
for breakfast to have a healthy heart
为了拥有健康的心脏
and cardiovascular system?
和心血管系统，您对我们早餐应该吃什么有什么建议？
&gt;&gt; Breakfast is a tough one. I tell most of
早餐是个难题。 我告诉
my patients that if you absolutely have
我的大多数病人，如果你非
to have a breakfast, have a couple of
要吃早餐，那就吃几个
eggs and if you are a vegetarian, it
鸡蛋；如果你是素食主义者，那就
makes it a little bit more tough. Um,
有点难办了。 嗯，
but you can have some kefir with two to
不过你可以在酸奶里加两到
three blueberries, two to three
三颗蓝莓、两到三颗
blackberries, and about four blueberries
黑莓，或者四颗左右的蓝莓
in it. And then you put your inulin
。 然后你把
powder in it and that's your breakfast.
菊粉放进去，这就是你的早餐。
That's all you should have. But a heavy
你只需要这些就够了。 但
breakfast and also breakfast in my
我认为，丰盛的早餐，以及早餐本身，
pass breakfast for most adults and just
对大多数成年人来说都应该略过，只吃
go for lunch and dinner only cuz then
午餐和晚餐，因为这样
you can do your 18 six. If you
你就可以完成你的18小时工作。 如果你
absolutely going to have breakfast then
一定要吃早餐，那就
you have breakfast and lunch and then no
吃早餐和午餐，然后
dinner. But you got to plan 18 hours. 18
晚餐就不吃了。 但你需要计划18个小时。  18
hours is optimal and we can do it. A lot
小时是最佳时长，我们可以做到。 很多
of people say they can do it, but most
人说他们能做到，但
of us can do it. You will notice how
我们大多数人都能做到。 你会发现
much more energy you have. You know,
自己精力充沛了很多。 你知道吗，
when I do my OMAD, which I do at least 3
当我实行 OMAD 饮食法时（我每周至少 3
to four times a week, which I only have
到 4 次，
one meal a day, at 6:00 in the evening,
每天只吃一顿饭，在晚上 6 点吃），
I actually have more energy than I do in
我的精力实际上比
the morning.
早上更充沛。
&gt;&gt; What does your diet look like, doctor?
医生，您的饮食习惯如何？
&gt;&gt; My diet? Yeah,
我的饮食？ 是的，
&gt;&gt; I do eat meat and I do eat fish,
我吃肉，也吃鱼、
chicken, and turkey and but I'll have I
鸡肉和火鸡，但我必须确保食材
source it right. Always make sure that
来源可靠。 务必确保
it's grass-finished. Always make sure
它是草饲的。 一定要买
it's organic and I'll have small amounts
有机的，而且我只会少量购买
of it.
。
&gt;&gt; Grass-fed, grass-fed.
草饲，草饲。
&gt;&gt; Grass finished.
草皮已完成。
&gt;&gt; What does that mean?
这意味着什么？
&gt;&gt; Grass-fed just means they took it out
草饲的意思就是他们有
one day and put it out in the field and
一天把牛赶到田里，
they fed it some grass. So, this
喂它吃些草。 所以，这个
advertising that industry does is a
行业的这种广告宣传
little deceiving.
有点欺骗性。
And I had to investigate this to find
我不得不对此进行调查才能弄清
out. It's a lie. It has to be grass-fed
。 这是谎言。 它必须从头到尾都以草为饲料
from beginning to end. So then it's
。 这样一来，它就会
going to have more omega-3 in it. It'll
含有更多的omega-3脂肪酸。 它会
have more K2 in it. It'll have more
含有更多的K2。 它营养更丰富，
nutrition and have less toxins also in
毒素含量也更低
it. So less omega6 because if your cows
。 所以，如果奶牛
are eating corn,
吃的是玉米，
then you're going to get all that
那么它们体内的 omega-6 就会减少，因为奶牛会摄入大量的
omega6. And the cow is not supposed to
omega-6。 牛不应该
be eating corn. Cow is supposed to be
吃玉米。 牛应该
eating grass.
吃草。
So I do eat some meats and I eat some
所以我吃一些肉，也会
vegetables with it. Coming from a
搭配一些蔬菜。
background, my great-grandfather's from
我的曾祖父来自印度，我出身于印度家庭
India. We do eat Indian food as well. So
。 我们也吃印度菜。 所以
we have some lentils
我们准备了一些扁豆，当然还有
and some curries of course. So we can
一些咖喱。 所以我们
cook the meats in a in a curry form as
也可以用咖喱的形式来烹饪肉类
well. I don't eat much chapatis because
。 我不太吃印度薄饼，因为
those are very full of carbs. I love the
那种饼碳水化合物含量很高。 我喜欢
taste of it. I love naan once in a
它的味道。 我偶尔会想吃馕
while.
。
&gt;&gt; And what do you supplement with? What's
那么你还会服用哪些补充剂？
your supplement stack look like? I take
你的营养补充剂组合是什么样的？ 我服用维生素
D3, K2,
D3、K2和
omega3 fish oil. So I take two two
omega-3鱼油。 所以我每天服用两粒
capsules every day. Vitamin C 1 g inulin
胶囊。 维生素C 1克菊粉开
kefir. I drink that every day and I
菲尔。 我每天都喝，而且我都会
count it. Magnesium
计算在内。
and I take nattokynise.
我服用镁和纳豆酮。
Nattokynise. Nattokynise I take about
纳托金尼斯。 我每天服用约 8000 单位的纳曲酮
8,000 units a day. What it is is that
。 它的作用是
it does thin the blood a little bit so
稍微稀释血液，
that you're less likely to make blood
从而降低血栓形成的可能性
clots. Part of metabolic syndrome is a
。 代谢综合征的一部分表现为
tendency to make blood clots and have a
容易形成血栓和
high fibbrin level. My frigen level was
纤维蛋白水平升高。 我的体温达到了
at the upper limits of normal. So I just
正常上限。 所以我只
take nattokinise. It doesn't cause any
服用纳豆酮。 它不会引起
bleeding or any problems like that. And
出血或其他类似问题。
then I also take a probiotic and I it's
然后我还服用益生菌，
it's basically is called mega spores
它基本上叫做巨型孢子
probiotic. So there's it's spores.
益生菌。 这就是它的孢子。
There's no real bacteria in there. It's
里面根本没有真正的细菌。
all spores.
全是孢子。
&gt;&gt; What's a spore?
什么是孢子？
&gt;&gt; A spore a bacteria
细菌
can survive
可以
by sporulating. So it becomes a spore.
通过形成孢子来存活。 于是它就变成了孢子。
So it's no longer a bacteria, it's a
所以它不再是细菌，而是
spore, but it'll germinate under the
孢子，但在合适的条件下会萌发
right circumstances. So these little
。 所以这些小
things, they have they are the spores of
东西，它们是
the bacteria that are in soil. So soil
土壤中细菌的孢子。 土壤中
has certain species of bacteria, the
含有某些种类的细菌，即
basilus species.
杆菌属细菌。
I consume, they go in my gut because
我摄入的孢子会进入我的肠道，因为
remember if I take a probiotic,
记住，如果我服用益生菌，
the acidity in my stomach is going to
胃里的酸性物质会
kill most of the bacteria.
杀死大部分细菌。
&gt;&gt; So what does a spore do? Sorry.
那么孢子究竟有什么作用呢？ 对不起。
&gt;&gt; So the spore passes through the stomach,
所以孢子会穿过胃，
goes all the way down to your intestines
一直到达肠道，
and then it germinates there. It grows
然后在那里发芽。 它在
there. So now the spore becomes a
那里生长。 所以现在孢子变成了
bacteria.
细菌。
&gt;&gt; Okay?
好的？
&gt;&gt; So it gets past that acidity of your
这样它就能克服
stomach. So, I do take that as a
胃酸的侵蚀。 所以，我也会服用这种
supplement as well.
补充剂。
&gt;&gt; Dr. Jay, what is the most important
杰伊博士，
should have talked about for the people
对于
at home that have clicked on this
在家点击观看这
episode? And you know, I guess one way
期节目的听众来说，我们最应该谈到但又没有谈到的最重要的事情是什么？ 你知道，我想
that you might tackle this question is
解决这个问题的一个方法是
just by thinking about the most popular
想想你
questions you get asked from your
的观众每天问你的最常见的问题，而
audience on a daily basis that we might
我们
not have covered today.
今天可能还没有讨论到这些问题。
&gt;&gt; How can I screen myself right now? What
我现在该如何进行自我筛查？
test should I do right now to see
我现在应该做什么检查来确定
coronary artery disease am I in? Because
我的炎症和冠状动脉疾病处于哪个阶段？ 因为
coronary arteries is the number one
冠状动脉疾病是导致
cause of death and inflammation is the
死亡的首要原因，而炎症是其
underlying cause. So what test should I
根本原因。 那我现在应该做哪项测试呢
be doing right now? That is an important
？ 这是一个重要的
question. If you're over the age of 30
问题。 如果你年满 30 岁
and you have concerns, one, get a
并且有任何疑虑，第一，去做个
coronary calcium score.
冠状动脉钙化评分。
If your coronary calcium score is zero,
如果你的冠状动脉钙化评分是零，说明
you have no calcium,
你体内没有钙化，
then you're in a good place. If you have
那么你的健康状况良好。 如果你有
coronary calcium,
冠状动脉钙化，
you need to go see a good cardiologist
你需要去看一位好的心脏病专家，他会为你制定
that's going to do a prevention program
预防方案，
because it means you already have
因为这意味着你已经患有动脉
athoscerosis.
粥样硬化。   动脉
&gt;&gt; Athoscerosis meaning plaque
粥样硬化是指
&gt;&gt; hardening of the arteries.
动脉内斑块硬化。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
。
&gt;&gt; Number two, you need a good blood test
第二，你需要做个好的血液检查
to look for inflammation. The blood test
来查找炎症。
that I order is called a Cleveland heart
我预约的血液检查是在克利夫兰心脏
labs. In it you get your HDL, LDL,
实验室进行的。 它能帮你测出高密度脂蛋白胆固醇、低密度脂蛋白
cholesterol. But you look at particle
胆固醇。 但你要看颗粒
sizes.
大小。
Is my LDL small dense? If it is small
我的低密度脂蛋白是小而密的吗？ 如果是细小的
dense particles, is it oxidized? Yes, I
致密颗粒，它是否被氧化了？ 是的，我
have a problem. My CRP level,
遇到了问题。 我的 CRP 水平、
other inflammatory interucan 6,
其他炎症因子 6、替
timonucosis factor, hemoglobin A1C,
莫诺西斯因子、糖化血红蛋白 A1C、
sugar level,
血糖水平，
all these are part of that panel of
所有这些都是该项
tests. So you should get a good
检测的一部分。 所以你应该去做个好的
inflammatory panel which is the
炎症指标检测，比如
Cleveland Heart Labs. So those are the
克利夫兰心脏实验室的检测。 所以，这两
two things that everyone must do. Get a
件事是每个人都必须做的。
coronary calcium score all adults and do
所有成年人均需进行冠状动脉钙化评分和
an inflammatory panel. Inflammation you
炎症指标检测。 炎症
got to know whether you look you know
需要了解，即使你看起来
you may not feel inflammation. It's not
可能没有炎症症状。 这
like you get a big pimple and it's going
不像长了个大痘痘会让
to hurt you but if you have inflammation
你疼，但如果身体出现炎症，
in the body yeah you could know about
你肯定会有感觉
it. How you have mental fog? I'm not
。 你为什么会感到思维混乱？ 我不是
optimal doc. My memor is going down. I'm
最佳医生。 我的内存正在下降。 我感到
depressed. Depression is inflammation.
抑郁。 抑郁症是一种炎症。
Depression is not something
抑郁症不是一种
psychological. Okay? Now, this I have to
心理疾病。 好的？ 现在，我必须
stress to you and I tell all my
向你们强调这一点，我也告诉我的所有
patients, you come in, I'm depressed.
病人，你们来的时候，我正处于抑郁状态。
You're depressed because
你之所以感到抑郁，是因为
that very symptom of depression is a
抑郁的这种症状本身就是
symptom of your inflammation.
你炎症的一种症状。
You can't be depressed about something
你不能因为“
that oh my car is not working very well.
哦，我的车不太好用”这种小事而感到沮丧。
That's a difference from depression.
这与抑郁症不同。
Depression is is is inflammation in the
抑郁症是
brain. So you'll be surprised how many
大脑炎症。 所以你会惊讶地发现，很多
patients go on my anti-inflammatory
病人都会采用我的抗炎
diet, which is I change the diet and fix
饮食，也就是改变他们的饮食，纠正他们的饮食习惯，
them all up and the depression goes
然后抑郁症就
away. So ask yourself not just questions
消失了。 所以，不仅要问问自己
about physically how you're feeling but
身体上的感受，还要问问自己
mentally also.
心理上的感受。
And if the answer is that doc I'm not
如果答案是医生，我状态
optimal I'm forgetful I'm depressed I'm
不佳，我健忘，我抑郁，我
having sleep dis disturbance I'm
睡眠紊乱，我的
relation things my I've changed my body
人际关系有问题，我的身体也发生了变化，而且
is also you have inflammation
你还有炎症，那么
we have a closing tradition on this
我们这个播客有个结束的传统，上
podcast where the last guest leaves a
一位嘉宾会给下一位嘉宾留下一个
question for the next guest not knowing
问题，而他们并不知道这个问题
who they're leaving it for and the
会留给谁。留给
question that's been left for you is
你的问题是：
what was the most difficult day of your
你生命中最艰难的一天是什么时候？
life and how did you overcome it
你是如何克服的？我
&gt;&gt; the most difficult day of my life
生命中最艰难的一天
was was a very personal one for me, you
对我来说非常私人，你
know, when when when when my my dad
知道，就是我父亲
passed away and you know, and I'm Dr.
去世的那天。我是杰伊医生，他当时
and when he he was sick and he didn't
生病了，不想
want to go to the hospital
去医院，然后
and then he passed away in his sleep and
在睡梦中去世了。
then you always ask yourself, could I
那时你总是会问自己，我是否可以
have done something differently? you
做些什么来改变这一切？ 你
know you second guess yourself and that
知道，你会对自己产生怀疑，这种
second guessing happened with him of
怀疑当然也发生在他身上，
course it was very very painful but it
这非常非常痛苦，但这种情况也会发生在其他
happens with patients as well but how
病人身上。但
did I overcome it it taught me a lot
我是如何克服的呢？它让我更清楚地认识到自己的
about my own limitations as well as a
局限性，无论作为一名
physician as a son as a scientist as a
医生、一个儿子、一个科学家还是一个
reader
读者，都是如此。这也是
and that's why I'm motivated to do what
我致力于
we are doing here also is to do the best
我们在这里所做的事情的原因，也是尽
you can to educate people What was he
我们所能去教育人们。他得了什么
sick with? What was his predicament?
病？ 他当时处境如何？
&gt;&gt; He was a cardiac patient already and
他原本就是心脏病患者，而且
he's he's got a very interesting story
他的故事其实非常有趣
actually. He was told that he only had a
。 他
few years to live after he had bypass
接受心脏搭桥手术后被告知，他只有几年的寿命了
surgery. But then I put him through all
。 但我随后让他体验了
the things we talked about today. He
我们今天讨论的所有事情。 他
lost a lot of weight. He went from 185
瘦了很多。 他的体重从185
lbs to 135 lbs. He changed his diet and
磅降到了135磅。 他改变了饮食习惯，又
he lived another 30 years and he did
活了30年，又进行了
another six world tours and traveled and
六次世界巡回演出，四处旅行，
he had a wonderful life. Okay. the
过着精彩的人生。 好的。
impact of simple things that we can do
我们可以通过一些简单的小事
to change his life. So he stopped
来改变他的生活。 所以他也戒了
drinking all alcohol as well and he he
酒，而且他的
really had a very clean diet and
饮食非常健康，
everything else. But that night he came
其他方面也都很注重健康。 但那天晚上他感染了
down with some sort of infection. He had
某种疾病。 他
massive diarrhea and massive massive
严重腹泻，并且发生了剧烈的
explosion. And I think that what really
爆炸。 我认为真正的原因
happened is he he got overwhelmed. You
是他压力过大了。 你
see it's the gut. He got overwhelmed
看，这就是肠胃。 他因
with a toxin from his gut and then he
肠道毒素过多而
passed away. But but here's a man who
去世。 但是，这里有一位
who lived to 89 who was supposed to have
活到 89 岁的人，他原本应该
passed away in his 60s and the impact
在 60 多岁就去世了，这造成了很大的影响，
but but the thing is that you know we we
但是，你知道，我们
we shouldn't second guessess ourselves.
不应该事后诸葛亮。
We don't want to live in the past.
我们不想活在过去。
I want to live in the present moment not
我只想活在当下，而不是活
even in the future.
在未来。
So all these things have taught me to
所以，所有这些经历都教会了我
live in the moment. And one of the
活在当下。
skills I've developed is just that that
我培养的一项技能就是，
when I'm with you, I'm only with you. If
当我和你在一起时，我的心就只有你。 如果让
I'm doing your surgery, I'm only doing
我给你做手术，我就只会给
your surgery. If I'm having a
你做手术。 如果我
conversation with you, you and I are the
和你聊天，那么此刻只有你和我两个
only people that matter right now. And
人最重要。 而
this being in the moment, that that
这种活在当下的
ability to be that is something I
能力，是我
learned over time because before you
随着时间的推移才学会的，因为在你
know something bad happens, your next
意识到糟糕的事情发生之前，在你处理下一个
case, you're still reminiscing about
案件之前，你还在回味之前的事情，
that and you're regretting that. You
并且为此感到后悔。 你
can't do that. Life is only expressed in
不能那样做。 生命只在
this moment right now. So learning how
此时此刻展现。 所以，学会
to live in the moment applies not only
活在当下不仅适用
to me but to everybody. We all living in
于我，也适用于所有人。 否则，我们都活在
the past otherwise and or we're worried
过去，或者我们都担忧
about the future. So how do you learn
未来。 那么，我们如何才能学会
present moment awareness and live in
觉察当下，活在此时此刻，
this moment so that we will be happier.
从而获得快乐呢？
We can do what we want to do. Make the
我们可以做我们想做的事。 做出
changes we need to make. get the courage
我们需要做出的改变。 鼓起勇气，
and make the and have the willpower to
做出改变，并拥有足够的意志力
go out and make a difference to yourself
走出去，为自己
and to everyone around you starts with
和周围的每个人带来改变，这一切都从
you being here. Are you here or are you
你来到这里开始。 你身处此地，还是身处过去，
in your past or have you gone off into
抑或已前往
the future? That's a skill that medicine
未来？ 这是医学
has taught me and I've become humbled by
教会我的一项技能，我从中受益匪浅，也让我更加谦逊
it. And this is something that I have
。 这是我
learned and I want to pass on to all my
学到的，我也想把它传递给我的所有
patients too as well that okay you've
病人：好吧，我知道你们有
got all these things going on but learn
很多事情要处理，但要学会
to live in the moment.
活在当下。
&gt;&gt; Dr. Jay, thank you so much. Thank you so
杰伊医生，非常感谢您。 非常感谢您
with so many people. If people aren't
与这么多人分享的智慧。 如果人们还不
familiar with you, you're extremely
认识你，那么你要知道，你是一位
prolific and well loved across the
在互联网上作品丰富、备受喜爱的人物，
internet for the the public education
因为
work you've done and the the heightening
你做了大量的公共教育工作，提高了
of awareness of people's heart and their
人们对心脏和
cardiovascular health more broadly. And
心血管健康的认识。
until really before you started making
直到你开始在
videos online, a lot of this stuff was
网上制作视频之前，很多这类事情都是
opaque. It was a mystery to a lot of
不透明的。 这对于很多人来说都是个谜
people. And your YouTube channel has
。 你的YouTube频道
almost a million subscribers now. And
现在已经拥有近百万订阅者了。 然后，
you you go through some of these
你会更详细地探讨
subjects that we've talked about today
我们今天讨论的一些主题
in even greater detail. So I'd highly
。 所以我强烈
recommend people go and check you out
建议大家去看看你
there. But also just thank you for
。 但也要感谢你
saving so many people's lives cuz you
拯救了那么多人的生命，因为你
know that's what you do day in day out
知道，这就是你日复一日所做的事情，
and that's an incredibly I mean there's
这是一种令人难以置信的使命，我的意思是，
probably not a higher calling one can
可能没有比这更高的使命了
answer. So thank you for doing what you
。 所以，感谢你所做的一切，
do and I can see now why people love
我现在明白为什么人们都喜欢
you. so much on online and on YouTube
你了。 因为你非常有魅力，而且很有智慧，所以我在网上和 YouTube 上看到了很多你的内容，
because you're so incredibly engaging, I
我
guess is the word, engaging, wise, and
觉得用“魅力”这个词来形容最贴切。
you make the information accessible in a
你以一种前所未有的方式让信息变得易于理解
before. So, thank you so much. It's a
。 非常感谢。 很
pleasure to meet you and to have this
高兴见到你，也很荣幸能
conversation with you, and thank you for
和你进行这次谈话，感谢你为
enlightening my audience.
我的听众带来启发。   这是
&gt;&gt; The pleasure was mine. Thank you.
我荣幸之至。 谢谢。
&gt;&gt; This has always blown my mind a little
这件事一直让我有点难以置信
bit. 53% of you that listen to the show
。 经常收听该节目的听众中，有 53% 的人
regularly haven't yet subscribed to the
尚未订阅该
show. So, could I ask you for a favor?
节目。 那么，我能请你帮个忙吗？
If you like the show and you like what
如果你喜欢我们的节目，喜欢
we do here and you want to support us,
我们在这里所做的一切，并且想要支持我们，最简单的
the free simple way that you can do just
免费方法
that is by hitting the subscribe button.
就是点击订阅按钮。
And my commitment to you is if you do
我向你们承诺，如果你们
that, then I'll do everything in my
这样做，
power, me and my team, to make sure that
我和我的团队将竭尽全力，确保
this show is better for you every single
这个节目每周都能为你们带来更好的体验
week. We'll listen to your feedback.
。 我们会认真听取您的反馈意见。
We'll find the guests that you want me
我们会找到您希望我
to speak to, and we'll continue to do
采访的嘉宾，并继续做好我们一直在做的事情
what we do. Thank you so much.
。 太感谢了。
[Music]
[音乐]
Heat. Heat. N.
热浪。热。N.